Running `python manage.py dumpdata --natural --indent 2 --format=yaml core` attached to terminal... up, run.1
- fields: {department: C, name: Learning Perl, number: 1, semester: U, year: 1996}
  model: core.course
  pk: 2
- fields: {department: M, name: Basic Algebra, number: 1, semester: F, year: 1993}
  model: core.course
  pk: 3
- fields: {department: M, name: Linear Algebra, number: 215, semester: F, year: 1995}
  model: core.course
  pk: 1
- fields: {department: C, name: Introduction to Programming with Java, number: 126,
    semester: F, year: 2011}
  model: core.course
  pk: 4
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 1, title: Vectors in 2- and 3-space}
  model: core.section
  pk: 1
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 2, title: Dot Products and Projections}
  model: core.section
  pk: 2
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 3, title: Lines and Planes in 3-space}
  model: core.section
  pk: 3
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 4, title: Systems of Linear Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 4
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 5, title: Matrices}
  model: core.section
  pk: 5
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 6, title: Inverses}
  model: core.section
  pk: 6
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 7, title: Elementary Matrices and Row Opeartions}
  model: core.section
  pk: 7
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 8, title: Main Theorem on Invertibility}
  model: core.section
  pk: 8
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 9, title: 'Diagonal, Triangular and Symmetric
      Matrices'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 9
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 10, title: The Determinant Function}
  model: core.section
  pk: 10
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 11, title: Evaluating Determinants}
  model: core.section
  pk: 11
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 12, title: Properties of Determinants}
  model: core.section
  pk: 12
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 13, title: Cofactor Expansion and Cramer's
      Rule}
  model: core.section
  pk: 13
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 14, title: Cross Product}
  model: core.section
  pk: 14
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 15, title: Euclidean $n$-space}
  model: core.section
  pk: 15
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 16, title: Linear Transformations of Euclidean
      $n$-space}
  model: core.section
  pk: 16
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 17, title: Properties of Linear Transformations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 17
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 18, title: Real Vector Spaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 18
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 19, title: Subspaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 19
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 20, title: Linear Independence}
  model: core.section
  pk: 20
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 21, title: Basis and Dimension}
  model: core.section
  pk: 21
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 22, title: 'Row Space, Column Space and
      Nullspace'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 22
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 23, title: Rank and Nullity}
  model: core.section
  pk: 23
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 24, title: Inner Product Spaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 24
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 25, title: Orthogonality}
  model: core.section
  pk: 25
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 26, title: Orthonormal Bases}
  model: core.section
  pk: 26
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 27, title: Best Approximation and Least
      Squares}
  model: core.section
  pk: 27
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 28, title: Orthogonal Matrices and Change
      of Basis}
  model: core.section
  pk: 28
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 29, title: Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors}
  model: core.section
  pk: 29
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 30, title: Diagonalization}
  model: core.section
  pk: 30
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 31, title: Orthogonal Diagonalization}
  model: core.section
  pk: 31
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 32, title: Approximation and Fourier Series}
  model: core.section
  pk: 32
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 33, title: General Linear Transformations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 33
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 34, title: Kernel and Range}
  model: core.section
  pk: 34
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 35, title: Inverse Linear Transformations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 35
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 36, title: Matrices of General Linear Transformations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 36
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 37, title: Similarity}
  model: core.section
  pk: 37
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 1, title: Number Properties}
  model: core.section
  pk: 41
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 2, title: Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 42
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 3, title: Exponents}
  model: core.section
  pk: 43
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 4, title: Roots}
  model: core.section
  pk: 44
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 5, title: Algebraic Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 45
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 6, title: Functions}
  model: core.section
  pk: 46
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 7, title: Graphs}
  model: core.section
  pk: 47
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 8, title: Systems of Two Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 48
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 9, title: Quadratic Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 49
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 10, title: Conics}
  model: core.section
  pk: 50
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 11, title: Polynomials}
  model: core.section
  pk: 51
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 12, title: Series}
  model: core.section
  pk: 52
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 13, title: 'Permutations, Combinations
      and the Binomial Formula'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 53
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 14, title: Induction}
  model: core.section
  pk: 54
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 15, title: Exponentials and Logarithms}
  model: core.section
  pk: 55
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 16, title: Multiple Equations}
  model: core.section
  pk: 56
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 17, title: Matrices}
  model: core.section
  pk: 57
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 19, title: Complex Numbers}
  model: core.section
  pk: 58
- fields: {category: L, course: 3, number: 18, title: Determinants}
  model: core.section
  pk: 59
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 38, title: Geometry of Linear Operators
      in R^2}
  model: core.section
  pk: 38
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 39, title: Quadratic Forms}
  model: core.section
  pk: 39
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 40, title: Diagonalizing Quadratic Forms}
  model: core.section
  pk: 40
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 41, title: Quadratic Surfaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 60
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 42, title: LU Decompositions}
  model: core.section
  pk: 61
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 43, title: Complex Vector Spaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 62
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 44, title: Complex Inner Product Spaces}
  model: core.section
  pk: 63
- fields: {category: L, course: 1, number: 45, title: 'Unitary, Normal and Hermitian
      Matrices'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 64
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 1, title: Prologue}
  model: core.section
  pk: 65
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 2, title: Introduction to Java}
  model: core.section
  pk: 66
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 3, title: Hello World}
  model: core.section
  pk: 67
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 4, title: Conditionals and Loops}
  model: core.section
  pk: 68
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 5, title: Arrays}
  model: core.section
  pk: 69
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 6, title: 'Conditionals,Loops Programs'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 70
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 7, title: Input and Output}
  model: core.section
  pk: 71
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 8, title: Functions}
  model: core.section
  pk: 72
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 9, title: N-Body Simulation}
  model: core.section
  pk: 73
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 10, title: Recursion}
  model: core.section
  pk: 74
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 12, title: Recursive Graphics}
  model: core.section
  pk: 75
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 13, title: Von Neumann Machine I}
  model: core.section
  pk: 76
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 14, title: Von Neumann Machine II}
  model: core.section
  pk: 77
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 15, title: Scientific Computing}
  model: core.section
  pk: 78
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 16, title: Hamming Codes}
  model: core.section
  pk: 79
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 17, title: Using Data Types}
  model: core.section
  pk: 80
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 18, title: Creating Data Types}
  model: core.section
  pk: 81
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 19, title: Linear Feedback Shift Register}
  model: core.section
  pk: 82
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 20, title: Stacks and Queues}
  model: core.section
  pk: 83
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 21, title: Symbol Tables}
  model: core.section
  pk: 84
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 22, title: Guitar Hero}
  model: core.section
  pk: 85
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 23, title: 'Case Study: Small World'}
  model: core.section
  pk: 86
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 24, title: Regular Expressions}
  model: core.section
  pk: 87
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 25, title: Markov Model}
  model: core.section
  pk: 88
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 26, title: Universality and Computability}
  model: core.section
  pk: 89
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 27, title: Intractability}
  model: core.section
  pk: 90
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 28, title: Traveling Salesperson Problem}
  model: core.section
  pk: 91
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 29, title: Circuits}
  model: core.section
  pk: 92
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 30, title: Architecture}
  model: core.section
  pk: 93
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 31, title: Atomic Nature of Matter}
  model: core.section
  pk: 94
- fields: {category: L, course: 4, number: 11, title: Performance}
  model: core.section
  pk: 95
- fields: {author: Howard Anton, edition: '', title: Elementary Linear Algebra}
  model: core.book
  pk: 1
- fields: {author: Douglas Downing, edition: 1st, title: Algebra the Easy Way}
  model: core.book
  pk: 2
- fields: {author: Theodore Shifrin, edition: '', title: 'Abstract Algebra: A Geometric
      Approach'}
  model: core.book
  pk: 3
- fields: {author: R. Sedgewick and K. Wayne, edition: '', title: 'Introduction to
      Programming in Java: An Interdisciplinary Approach'}
  model: core.book
  pk: 4
- fields: {name: Geometric Vectors, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 1
- fields: {name: Geometry of Vector Arithmetic, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 2
- fields: {name: Vectors in Coordinate Systems, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 3
- fields: {name: Translation of Axes, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 4
- fields: {name: 8 properties of vectors in 2- or 3-space, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 5
- fields: {name: Norm of a vector, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 6
- fields: {name: Unit Vectors, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 7
- fields: {name: Distance between vectors, section: 1}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 8
- fields: {name: Planes in 3-space, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 9
- fields: {name: General form of equation of a plane in 3-space, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 10
- fields: {name: Vector Form of the equation of a plane, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 11
- fields: {name: Parametric equations for lines in 3-space, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 12
- fields: {name: Vector form of the equation of a line, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 13
- fields: {name: Distance between a point and a plane., section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 14
- fields: {name: Distance between 2 parallel planes, section: 3}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 15
- fields: {name: Dot Product of Vectors, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 16
- fields: {name: Component formula for the dot product of vectors, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 17
- fields: {name: Finding the angle between vectors, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 18
- fields: {name: Orthogonal vectors, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 19
- fields: {name: 4 properties of dot products of vectors in 2- and 3-space, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 20
- fields: {name: orthogonal projections, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 21
- fields: {name: complement of orthogonal projection, section: 2}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 22
- fields: {name: Linear Systems, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 23
- fields: {name: Elementary Row Operations, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 24
- fields: {name: Reduced Row-Echelon Form, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 25
- fields: {name: Gaussian Elimination, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 26
- fields: {name: Back-Substitution, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 27
- fields: {name: Homogeneous Linear Systems, section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 28
- fields: {name: For a H.L.S. where unknowns > equations implies infinitely many solutions.,
    section: 4}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 29
- fields: {name: Matrices, section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 30
- fields: {name: Matrix Arithmetic (not including multiplication), section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 31
- fields: {name: Matrix Multiplication, section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 32
- fields: {name: Partition matrices and multiplication, section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 33
- fields: {name: Transpose of a matrix, section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 34
- fields: {name: Trace of a matrix, section: 5}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 35
- fields: {name: Invertibility of a transpose, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 36
- fields: {name: 13 properties of matrix arithmetic, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 37
- fields: {name: zero matrix and identity properties, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 38
- fields: {name: Identity matrix and identity properties, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 39
- fields: {name: inverse of a matrix, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 40
- fields: {name: An invertible matrix has exactly one inverse, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 41
- fields: {name: Inverses of AB, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 42
- fields: {name: powers of a matrix, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 43
- fields: {name: Properties of the transpose, section: 6}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 44
- fields: {name: Elementary matrices, section: 7}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 45
- fields: {name: 'Relationship b/w elementary matrices, H.L.S, invertibility and r.r-e
      form.', section: 7}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 46
- fields: {name: Row equivalence, section: 7}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 47
- fields: {name: Algorithm for matrix inversion via Gaussian elemination, section: 7}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 48
- fields: {name: 'System of linear equations have 0, 1 or $\infty$ solutions', section: 8}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 49
- fields: {name: Right or left inverses suffice, section: 8}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 50
- fields: {name: Main theorem on inveritibilty v2, section: 8}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 51
- fields: {name: Diagonal Matrices, section: 9}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 52
- fields: {name: Triangular matrices and invertibility, section: 9}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 53
- fields: {name: Symmetric matrices and inverses, section: 9}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 54
- fields: {name: Matrices of the form $AA^T$ or $A^TA$, section: 9}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 55
- fields: {name: Permutations basics (enough for determinants), section: 10}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 56
- fields: {name: Definition of a determinant in terms of signed elementary products,
    section: 10}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 57
- fields: {name: Determinant function, section: 10}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 58
- fields: {name: $2\times2$ and $3\times3$ determinant formula, section: 10}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 59
- fields: {name: 'Det lemma: row or column of zeros imply det = 0', section: 11}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 60
- fields: {name: Determinant of triangular matrices, section: 11}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 61
- fields: {name: Effect of elementary row operations on a determinant, section: 11}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 62
- fields: {name: Determinants of elementary matrices, section: 11}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 63
- fields: {name: Determinants calculated by row reduction, section: 11}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 64
- fields: {name: Det of sums and scalar products, section: 12}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 65
- fields: {name: Determinant of matrix product via elementary decomposition, section: 12}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 66
- fields: {name: Determinant test for invertibility, section: 12}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 67
- fields: {name: Systems of the form $Ax = \lambda x$, section: 12}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 68
- fields: {name: Minors and Cofactors, section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 69
- fields: {name: Determinants via Cofactor expansion, section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 70
- fields: {name: Adjoint of a matrix, section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 71
- fields: {name: Adjoint formula for the inverse of a matrix - a theoretical formula,
    section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 72
- fields: {name: Cramer's Rule, section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 73
- fields: {name: Application of adjoint formula to triangular matrices, section: 13}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 74
- fields: {name: Cross product of vectors, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 75
- fields: {name: Basic properties of cross products, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 76
- fields: {name: Determinant formula for cross product, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 77
- fields: {name: Geometric interpretation of cross product, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 78
- fields: {name: Scalar triple product, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 79
- fields: {name: Geometric interpretation of determinants, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 80
- fields: {name: independence of cross products and coordinates, section: 14}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 81
- fields: {name: Vectors in $n$-space, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 82
- fields: {name: 8 basic properties of $n$-space, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 83
- fields: {name: Euclidean inner-product and it's basic properties, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 84
- fields: {name: Norm and distance in Euclidean $n$-space, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 85
- fields: {name: 'Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality in $\mathbf{R}^n$', section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 86
- fields: {name: Basic properties of norm and distance in Euclidean $n$-space, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 87
- fields: {name: Orthogonality in Euclidean $n$-space, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 88
- fields: {name: 'Theorem of Pythagoras for $\mathbb{R}^n$', section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 89
- fields: {name: A dot product view of matrix multiplication, section: 15}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 90
- fields: {name: 'Review of Functions from $\mathbb{R}^n \to $\mathbb{R}$', section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 91
- fields: {name: 'Functions from $\mathbb{R}^n \to $\mathbb{R}^m$', section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 92
- fields: {name: LInear transformations, section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 93
- fields: {name: Projection Operators, section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 94
- fields: {name: Rotation Operators, section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 95
- fields: {name: Dilation and Contraction Operators, section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 96
- fields: {name: Composition of Linear Transformations, section: 16}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 97
- fields: {name: One-to-one linear transformations and relation to underlying matrix,
    section: 17}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 98
- fields: {name: Inverse of a one-to-one linear operator, section: 17}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 99
- fields: {name: Linearity properties, section: 17}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 100
- fields: {name: Representation of matrix in terms of images of standard basis vectors,
    section: 17}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 101
- fields: {name: Geometric interpretation of Eigenvectors, section: 17}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 102
- fields: {name: Axioms of Real vector spaces, section: 18}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 103
- fields: {name: Examples of various vectors spaces and non-spaces, section: 18}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 104
- fields: {name: properties of 0 and -1 in a vector space, section: 18}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 105
- fields: {name: Definition of a subspace, section: 19}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 106
- fields: {name: Examples of subspaces, section: 19}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 107
- fields: {name: Solution space of H.L.S. as a subspace, section: 19}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 108
- fields: {name: Linear combinations of vectors, section: 19}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 109
- fields: {name: Definition of spaning space, section: 19}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 110
- fields: {name: 'Definition of Linearly [in]dependent sets', section: 20}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 111
- fields: {name: Explanation of L.I. in terms of expressibility in L.C., section: 20}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 112
- fields: {name: Geometric interpretation of L.I., section: 20}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 113
- fields: {name: Wronskian and linear independence of functions, section: 20}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 114
- fields: {name: Definition of a basis, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 115
- fields: {name: Coordinates relative to a basis, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 116
- fields: {name: Standard bases, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 117
- fields: {name: Key lemma in proof of well-defined dimension, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 118
- fields: {name: Dimension of a vector space, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 119
- fields: {name: Plus/Minus theorem, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 120
- fields: {name: Dimension and subspaces, section: 21}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 121
- fields: {name: 'Definition of Row, Column and nullspaces', section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 122
- fields: {name: Relationship between consistent systems and column spaces, section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 123
- fields: {name: Relationships between solutions of Ax=b and $Ax=0, section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 124
- fields: {name: Effect of elementary row operations on null and row spaces, section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 125
- fields: {name: row equivalence preservers L.I., section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 126
- fields: {name: 'Finding row, column and nullspace bases', section: 22}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 127
- fields: {name: Row space and column space have the same dimension, section: 23}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 128
- fields: {name: Definition of rank and nullity, section: 23}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 129
- fields: {name: Dimension theorem (also known as rank-nullity theorem), section: 23}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 130
- fields: {name: The Consistency theorem, section: 23}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 131
- fields: {name: Relationship between rank and consistent linear systems, section: 23}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 132
- fields: {name: Axioms of a real inner product space, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 133
- fields: {name: Weighted inner products, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 134
- fields: {name: Length and distance in inner product spaces, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 135
- fields: {name: Unit spheres, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 136
- fields: {name: Inner product spaces generated by matrices, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 137
- fields: {name: 5 basic properties of inner products, section: 24}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 138
- fields: {name: Cauchy-Schwarz Inequality in an inner product space, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 139
- fields: {name: 4 properties of length and 4 properties of distance in inner product
      spaces, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 140
- fields: {name: Angle between vectors, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 141
- fields: {name: Orthogonality in inner product spaces, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 142
- fields: {name: Generalized theorem of Pythagoras, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 143
- fields: {name: Orthogonal Complements, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 144
- fields: {name: Geometric link between nullspace and rowspaces, section: 25}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 145
- fields: {name: Orthogonal or Orthonormal bases, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 146
- fields: {name: Coordinates relative to orthonormal basis, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 147
- fields: {name: Coordinates relative to orthogonal bases, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 148
- fields: {name: Orthogonal projection and the projection theorem, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 149
- fields: {name: Gram-Schmidt process, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 150
- fields: {name: QR-decomposition, section: 26}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 151
- fields: {name: Best Approximation theorem and orthogonal projection, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 152
- fields: {name: The least squares problem, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 153
- fields: {name: normal systems and the solution of, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 154
- fields: {name: Uniqueness of Least Squares Solutions, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 155
- fields: {name: Orthogonal Projection Operator, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 156
- fields: {name: Least squares solution, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 157
- fields: {name: Least squares fit of a polynomial, section: 27}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 158
- fields: {name: Orthogonal matrix and three definitions, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 159
- fields: {name: Orthogonal matrices as linear operators, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 160
- fields: {name: Change of basis problem, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 161
- fields: {name: Solution to the change of basis problem, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 162
- fields: {name: Transition matrix, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 163
- fields: {name: Transition matrices are invertible and intepretation of the inverse,
    section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 164
- fields: {name: Transition matrices between orthonormal bases, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 165
- fields: {name: Application to Rotation of Coordinate Axes, section: 28}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 166
- fields: {name: Review of eigen stuff, section: 29}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 167
- fields: {name: Eigenvalues of triangular matrices, section: 29}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 168
- fields: {name: Finding bases for eigenspaces, section: 29}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 169
- fields: {name: Eigenvalues of the powers of a matrix, section: 29}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 170
- fields: {name: Eigenvalues and invertibility, section: 29}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 171
- fields: {name: The Eigenvalue problem, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 172
- fields: {name: The Diagonalization problem, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 173
- fields: {name: Equivalence of Eigenvalue and Diagonalization problem, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 174
- fields: {name: Procedure to diagonalize a matrix, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 175
- fields: {name: Eigenvectors from distinct eigenvalues are L.I., section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 176
- fields: {name: Criteria for matrix to be diagonalizable, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 177
- fields: {name: Geometric and algebraic multiplicity, section: 30}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 178
- fields: {name: Orthogonal eigenvector problem, section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 179
- fields: {name: Orthogonal diagonalization problem, section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 180
- fields: {name: Orthogonally diagonalizable iff symmetric, section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 181
- fields: {name: eigenvectors from different eigenspaces are orthgonal in a symmetric
      matrix, section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 182
- fields: {name: Procedure for diagonalization of symmetric matrices, section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 183
- fields: {name: 'Statement that eigenvalues of symmetric matrix are real, but no
      proof.', section: 31}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 184
- fields: {name: The Approximation Problem, section: 32}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 185
- fields: {name: Mean Square error, section: 32}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 186
- fields: {name: Least Squares Approximation Problem, section: 32}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 187
- fields: {name: Solution of Least Squares Approximation Problem, section: 32}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 188
- fields: {name: Fourier Series, section: 32}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 189
- fields: {name: General Linear Transformation, section: 33}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 190
- fields: {name: Examples of General Linear Transformations, section: 33}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 191
- fields: {name: 3 Properties of G.L.T., section: 33}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 192
- fields: {name: Finding linear transformations from images of basis vectors, section: 33}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 193
- fields: {name: Composition of General linear transformations, section: 33}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 194
- fields: {name: Definition of Kernel and Range, section: 34}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 195
- fields: {name: Kernel and Range are subspaces, section: 34}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 196
- fields: {name: Rank and nullity of G.L.T. relation to rank and nullity of matrix,
    section: 34}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 197
- fields: {name: Dimension theorem for G.L.T., section: 34}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 198
- fields: {name: One-to-one G.L.T., section: 35}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 199
- fields: {name: 'Relationship between one-to-one GLT, Kernel and nullity', section: 35}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 200
- fields: {name: Inverse linear transformation, section: 35}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 201
- fields: {name: Inverses of compositions of GLT, section: 35}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 202
- fields: {name: Matrices of Linear Transformations, section: 36}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 203
- fields: {name: Matrices of Linear Operators, section: 36}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 204
- fields: {name: Matrices of compositions and inverse transformations of a G.L.T.,
    section: 36}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 205
- fields: {name: Relationship b/w transition matrices and identity operators, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 206
- fields: {name: Effect of changing bases on matrices of linear operators, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 207
- fields: {name: Definition of similar matrices, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 208
- fields: {name: Examples of similarity invariants, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 209
- fields: {name: Geometric interpretation of similarity invariants, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 210
- fields: {name: Eigenstuff of GLT, section: 37}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 211
- fields: {name: Quadratic form in n variables, section: 38}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 212
- fields: {name: The 4 main problems on quadratic forms, section: 38}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 213
- fields: {name: Solution to the max/min problem of quadratic forms, section: 38}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 214
- fields: {name: Positive definit matrices and forms, section: 38}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 215
- fields: {name: Principal submatrices, section: 38}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 216
- fields: {name: Diagonalization of quadratic forms, section: 39}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 217
- fields: {name: Conic sections, section: 39}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 218
- fields: {name: Cross-term products, section: 39}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 219
- fields: {name: Elimination of cross-term products, section: 39}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 220
- fields: {name: 'Principal Axes theorem for $\mathbb{R}^2$', section: 39}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 221
- fields: {name: Definition of a quadratic surface, section: 40}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 222
- fields: {name: Eliminating cross-product terms in quadratic surfaces, section: 40}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 223
- fields: {name: 'Principal Axes theorem for $\mathbb{R}^3$', section: 40}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 224
- fields: {name: Basic Static Method Writing, section: 72}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 225
- fields: {name: Static Methods With Array Arguments and Side Effects on Arrays, section: 72}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 226
- fields: {name: Using Static methods in other programs, section: 72}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 227
- fields: {name: 'Libraries, Clients and APIs', section: 72}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 228
- fields: {name: Unit Testing, section: 72}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 229
- fields: {name: Basic Recursion, section: 74}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 230
- fields: {name: Towers of Hanoi, section: 74}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 231
- fields: {name: Function Call Trees, section: 74}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 232
- fields: {name: Recursion and Recurrence Relations, section: 74}
  model: core.concept
  pk: 233
- fields:
    answer: "When they have the same length and same direction, even if the initial\
      \ andterminal points are not the same.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: Define when two vectors are equivalent.
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 1
- fields:
    answer: "<ul>\r\n<li> The midpoint is $\\frac{P+Q}{2} = (\\frac{9}{2}, -\\frac{1}{2},\
      \ -\\frac{1}{2}).$\r\n<li> The point $\\frac{3}{4}$ of the way from $P$ to $Q$\
      \ is $P + \\frac{3}{4}(Q - P) = \\frac{1}{4}P + \\frac{3}{4}Q = (\\frac{23}{4},\
      \ -\\frac{9}{4}, \\frac{1}{4}).$\r\n</ul>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: X
    concepts: [3]
    index: 3.1.11
    points: 4
    question: "Let $P$ be the point $(2, 3, -2)$ and $Q$ be the point $(7, -4, 1)$.\r\
      \n<ul>\r\n<li> Find the midpoint of the line segment connecting $P$ and $Q$.\r\
      \n<li> Find the point on the line segment connecting $P$ and $Q$ that is $\\\
      frac{3}{4}$ of the way from $P$ to $Q$.\r\n</ul>"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 2
- fields:
    answer: "Suppose neither $a$ nor $b$ are 0. Then:\r\n\r\n$1 = 1/a 1/b ab = 1/a\
      \ 1/b 0 = 0$.\r\n\r\nThus we have a contradiction, and one of $a$ or $b$ is\
      \ zero."
    book: 3
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: If $ab = 0$ and $a$ and $b$ are real numbers, what can you say?
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 3
- fields:
    answer: "A number is prime if $p > 1$ and its only positive divisors are $1$ and\
      \ $p$.\r\n"
    book: 3
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: Define a prime number $p \in \mathbb{N}$
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 4
- fields:
    answer: "$$3 \\times 14 = 42$$\r\n$$3 \\times 4 + 3 \\times 10 = 12 + 30 = 42$$\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.9'
    points: 2
    question: "Verify the distributive property\r\n\r\n$$3 \\times (4 + 10)$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 5
- fields:
    answer: "$$0$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '3.16'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify \r\n$$-3 \\cdot (-6 + 6)$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 6
- fields:
    answer: "$$4/15 + 7/48 = \\frac{4 \\times 16 + 7 \\times 5}{16 \\times 5 \\times\
      \ 3} = \\frac{48+35}{240} = \\frac{83}{240}$$\r\n$$1.41 + 0.564 + 0.0141 = 1.9881$$\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '4'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 4.12, 4.36
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify\r\n$$1/3 \\times 4/5 + 1/6 \\times 7/8$$\r\n$$1.41 \\times\
      \ 1.41$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 7
- fields:
    answer: "2, 3, 5, 7, 11, 13, 17, 19\r\n"
    book: 3
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.2'
    points: 1
    question: List all prime numbers less than 20
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 8
- fields:
    answer: "If $a$ is divisible by $n$, then $a = kn$ and if $m$ is not then $m =\
      \ k'n + c$\r\nwhere $c \\ne 0$. Then note that $a + b = (k+k')n + c$, so $a+b$\
      \ is NOT\r\ndivisible by $n$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.37'
    points: 3
    question: "If you add one number divisible by $n$ and one number not divisible\
      \ by $n$,\r\nwill the result be divisible by $n? Explain."
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 9
- fields:
    answer: "When $a$ and $b$ have the same sign.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '3.39'
    points: 2
    question: "When does \r\n$$|a + b| = |a| + |b|?$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 10
- fields:
    answer: "1) a + b = b + a\r\n2) (a + b) + c = a + (b + c)\r\n3) 0 + a = a\r\n\
      4) a + (-a) = 0\r\n5) a x b = b x a\r\n6) (a x b) x c = a x (b x c)\r\n7) a\
      \ x 1 = a\r\n8) a x (b + c) = a x b + a x c\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: '1'
    points: 4
    question: State the eight algebraic properties of the integers
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 11
- fields:
    answer: "Any correct transformation to two equal quantities results in two other\
      \ equal\r\nquantities."
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the golden rule\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 12
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = \\frac{d - b}{a - c}.$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '2.18'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $x$\r\n$$ax - b = cx + d.$$"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 13
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n$$ x + (x+1) + (x+2) = 75$$\r\n$$ 3x + 3 = 75$$\r\n$$ 3x = 72$$\r\
      \n$$  x = 24$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '2.29'
    points: 4
    question: "What three consecutive numbers add up to 75?\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 14
- fields:
    answer: "1. Reflexive: $a = a$.\r\n2. Symmetry: $a = b$ implies $b = a$.\r\n3.\
      \ Transitive: $a = b$ and $b = c$ implies $a = c$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State the properties of equality.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 15
- fields:
    answer: "You can start with squares, cubes, etc. as very common operations (e.g.\
      \ area),\r\nand then notice that you can extend."
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the motivation behind exponent conventions.\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 16
- fields:
    answer: "Simplify:\r\n$$16a^3b^4c/(8a^3b^6c^2)$$"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '5.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify:\r\n$$16a^3b^4c/(8a^3b^6c^2)$$\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 17
- fields:
    answer: "$1.098 \\times 10^12$ cubic kilometers.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '5.33'
    points: 5
    question: "The volume of a sphere is given by the formula $(4/3\\pi r^3$,where\
      \ $\\pi$ is about 3.14 and $r$ is the radius of the sphere. The earth is approximately\
      \ a sphere with radius about $6400$ kilometers. What is the volume of the earth\
      \ (use scientific notation)?\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 18
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^a x^b = x^{a+b}$$\r\n$$(x^a)^b = x^{ab}$$\r\n$$\\frac{x^a}{x^b} =\
      \ x^{a-b}$$\r\n$$(xy)^a = x^ay^a$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 4
    question: "What are the Laws of Exponents?\r\n\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 19
- fields:
    answer: "When examining the diagonal of a unit square\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example of how a square root arises in geometry.\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 20
- fields:
    answer: "$3/4$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.3'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify $\\sqrt{9/16}$.\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 21
- fields:
    answer: "$-3 - 2\\sqrt{2}$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.17'
    points: 1
    question: "Remove the radical from the denominator of $\\frac{1 + \\sqrt{2}}{1\
      \ - \\sqrt{2}}$.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 22
- fields:
    answer: "$\\frac{1}{4}$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.26'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify $\\sqrt[4]{1/256}$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 23
- fields:
    answer: "The goal is to simplify the complexity of the algebraic expression, by\
      \ either\r\nproducing fewer terms or perhaps fewer factors\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain the goal of the Algebraic Expression Rule\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 24
- fields:
    answer: "1. $(a + b)^2 = a^2 + 2ab + b^2$\r\n\r\n2. $(a - b)^2 = a^2 - 2ab + b^2$\r\
      \n\r\n3. $(a - b)(a + b) = a^2 - b^2$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State 3 generic rules involving combining $(a+b)$ and $(a-b)$.\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 25
- fields:
    answer: "A collection of numbers and letters representing numbers that are connected\
      \ by arithmetic operation signs, such as $+$, $-$, $/$ or $\\cdot$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an algebraic expression\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 26
- fields:
    answer: "The part of an algebraic expression that are separated by $\\pm$.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a term\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 27
- fields:
    answer: "A 1-, 2-, or 3-term algebraic expression [resp.]\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define monomomial, binomial and trinomial algebraic expressions.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 28
- fields:
    answer: "$$6x^2 + 2x + 12ax + 2a + 6a^2 - 4$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.23'
    points: 1
    question: "Multiply $[(2x + 1) + (2a + 1)][(3x - 1) + (3a - 1)]$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 29
- fields:
    answer: "$$1 + 3x + 3x^2 + x^3$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.25'
    points: 1
    question: "Multiply out $(1+x)^3$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 30
- fields:
    answer: "$$[x^2 - 6x + 9]/16 + [y^2 + 6y + 9]/9 = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.32'
    points: 3
    question: "Write the following algebraic expression in the form $Ax^2 + Bxy +\
      \ Cy^2 + Dx + Ey + F = 0$:\r\n$$(x - 3)^2/16 + (y + 3)^2/9 = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 31
- fields:
    answer: "$$= (155 - 154)(155 + 154) = 1 \\cdot 309 = 309$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.35'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate: 155^2 - 154^2 simply.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 32
- fields:
    answer: "Combine all of the like terms into one term.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Algebraic Expression Rule\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 33
- fields:
    answer: "$$a(b+c) = ab + bc$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Distributive property of algebraic expressions.\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 34
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a + b)(c + d) = ac + ad + bc + bd\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the FOIL method\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 35
- fields:
    answer: "Consider a table of values for common values: area versus side length,\
      \ fall\r\ntime versus drop height, etc. This will lead to the idea of a function\
      \ as a\r\nshortcut.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Give a motivation for the development of functions\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 36
- fields:
    answer: "A function $f$ is an assignment of a value $y$ to any quantity $x$. We\
      \ denote\r\nthis assignment as $y = f(x)$. The set of possible $x$ is called\
      \ the domain,\r\nand the set of possible $y$ is called the range.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Define a function, domain and range.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 37
- fields:
    answer: "$g$ is the inverse of $f$ if for all $x$, $f(g(x)) = x$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an inverse function\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 38
- fields:
    answer: "2, 1, $a^2 + 2a + 2$, $2xh + 2h + h^2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 8.11, 13, 15, 17
    points: 4
    question: "Let $f(x) = x^2 + 2x + 2$. Evaluate: $f(0), $f(-1)$, $f(a)$, $f(x +\
      \ h) - f(x)$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 39
- fields:
    answer: "The first number is the distance east of the origin while the second\
      \ number is\r\nthe distance north."
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how a pair of numbers represents a point in a north-east plane.\r\
      \n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 40
- fields:
    answer: "A pair of numbers written $(x, y)$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an ordered pair\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 41
- fields:
    answer: "$$m = \\frac{ y_2 - y_1 }{ x_2 - x_1 }$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the slope of the line going between the points $(x_1, y_1)$\
      \ and $(x_2, y_2)$?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 42
- fields:
    answer: "The y value of where the x-value is zero.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the y-intercept of a line\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 43
- fields:
    answer: "17.464\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.6'
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance between $(16, 4)$ and $(0, -3)$?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 44
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 4
    question: "Draw the graph of $y = |x + 2| - 2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 45
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 0, y = 10; x = 5, y = 0$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.16'
    points: 3
    question: "Find the coordinates of the points where the line $2x + y = 10$ cross\
      \ the $x$ and $y$ axes.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 46
- fields:
    answer: "$$(y - 1030)/(x - 1025) = 100; y = 100x - 101470$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.24'
    points: 5
    question: "Find the equation of a line with slope $100$ and passes through the\
      \ point $(1025, 1030)$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 47
- fields:
    answer: "$$d = \\sqrt{x^2 + y^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance from the origin of a point $(x, y)$?\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 48
- fields:
    answer: "$$d = \\sqrt{ (x_2 - x_1)^2 + (y_2 - y_1)^2 }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance between two points $(x_1, y_1)$ and $(x_2, y_2)$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 49
- fields:
    answer: "$$y = mx + b$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "If $m$ is the slope of a line and $b$ is the $y$-intercept, what is\
      \ the\r\nequation of the line?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 50
- fields:
    answer: "When two graphs (of $f$ and $g$) intersect, then $f(x) = g(x)$ thus it's\
      \ a\r\nsolution to two simultaneous equations."
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain what the intersection of two graphs represents?\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 51
- fields:
    answer: "Solve one equation for x, substitute this into the second, solve for\
      \ y, and\r\nthen back-solve for x."
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to solve a system of two linear equations\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 52
- fields:
    answer: "They are the same line.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "If two simultaneous linear equations have no solution what does this\
      \ say about the lines?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 53
- fields:
    answer: "Two equations:\r\n$$y = f(x)$$\r\n$$y = g(x)$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a system of two simultaneous equations.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 54
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 4, y = 18$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.1 and 10.3
    points: 3
    question: "Solve the following systems of equations for x and y:\r\n\r\n$$y =\
      \ 10 + 2x$$\r\n$$y = 4.5x$$\r\n\r\n$$y = 10 + 2x$$\r\n$$y = 2x$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 55
- fields:
    answer: "12 cows and 21 chickens\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '10.29'
    points: 4
    question: "Farmer Floran has a total 33 cows and chickens. Altogether the\r\n\
      animals have 90 feet. How many cows and how many chickens are there?\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 56
- fields:
    answer: "If we can write $ax^2 + bx +c = d(x - e)(x - f) = 0$ then if $d \\ne\
      \ 0$, since\r\ntwo non-zero numbers cannot multiply to be zero (See\r\nAlgebra/000/Number_Properties)\
      \ one of $x - e = 0$ or $x - f = 0$, or\r\nequivalently, $ x = e $ or $x = f$."
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to solve a quadratic equation via factoring.\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 57
- fields:
    answer: "If the coefficients of the equation are all rational, then no.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Can a quadratic equation have one rational solution and one irrational?\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 58
- fields:
    answer: "If $b^2 - 4ac$ is a square.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give a condition for whether the solutions to a quadratic equation\
      \ will be\r\nrational.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 59
- fields:
    answer: "A polynomial is a multinomial in which each term contains $x$ raises\
      \ to a\r\nwhole-number power.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a polynomial\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 60
- fields:
    answer: "The degree is the highest power of $x$. A quadratic is a second-degree\r\
      \npolynomial.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the degree of a polynomial. Define a quadratic polynomial\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 61
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = -1/3, -3$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.25'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve \r\n$$y^2 + (3 1/3)y + 1 = 0$$\r\nby factoring.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 62
- fields:
    answer: "1. Yes\r\n2. No\r\n3. No.\r\n4. Yes\r\n5. It can be transformed into\
      \ a polynomial.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 11.30-34
    points: 2
    question: "Which of these algebraic expressions are polynomials:\r\n1. $2^2 -\
      \ 6x - 4$\r\n2. $x^3 + x^2 + x + 1 + x^{-1} + x^{-2} + x^{-3}$\r\n3. $(x^2 +\
      \ 3x + 4)/(x-5)$\r\n4. $(1/2)gt^2 + 40$\r\n5. $(1/y)(y^3 + 3y^2 + 3y + y)$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 63
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 3, -6$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.43'
    points: 3
    question: "Solve \r\n$$x^2 + 3x - 18 = 0$$\r\nby using the quadratic equation.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 64
- fields:
    answer: "x = -2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.57'
    points: 1
    question: "Solve for $x$:\r\n$$2/x + 4/x^2 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 65
- fields:
    answer: "$x = 3, 2$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.59'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $x$:\r\n$$\\sqrt{5x - 6} = x$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 66
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^2 - 4x - 1 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.68'
    points: 2
    question: "Create a quadratic equation with solutions $x = 2 + \\sqrt{5}$ or\r\
      \n$x = 2 - \\sqrt{5}$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 67
- fields:
    answer: "Consider a general quadratic and complete the square:\r\n$$ax^2 + bx\
      \ + c = 0$$\r\n$$x^2 + bx/a + c/a = 0$$\r\n$$x^2 + bx/a + c/a -c/a + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2\
      \ = -c/a + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = -c/a + \\\
      frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = -ca/a^2 + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\
      \n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = (-4ca + b)/(4a^2)$$\r\n$$x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a)\
      \ = \\pm sqrt{-4ca + b}/(2a)$$\r\n$$x = \\frac{-b \\pm sqrt{b-4ac}}{2a}$$\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 5
    question: "Prove the quadratic formula\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 68
- fields:
    answer: "$$(x +\\frac{1}{2}b)^2 = x^2 + bx + \\frac{1}{4}b^2$$\r\nSo add $\\frac{1}{4}b^2\
      \ - c$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Given $x^2 + bx +c = 0$, what do you need to add to complete the square?\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 69
- fields:
    answer: "Factor out $a$ and complete the square. Then write\r\n$$(x- h)^2 + k$$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how to deal with non-monic quadratics w.r.t. completing the\
      \ square.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 70
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = \\frac{-b \\pm \\sqrt{ b^2 - 4ac } }{2a}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the quadratic equation:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 71
- fields:
    answer: "A circle is the set of points (in a plane) such that every point on the\
      \ circle\r\nis the same distance (called the radius) from a fixed point (called\
      \ the\r\ncenter).\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a circle\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 72
- fields:
    answer: "An ellipse is the set of all points (in a plane) such that the sum of\
      \ the\r\ndistances to two fixed points is a constant. The two fixed points are\
      \ called\r\nthe foci.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Define an ellipse\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 73
- fields:
    answer: "It is the distance between focal points divided by the length of the\
      \ major\r\naxis.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the eccentricity of an ellipse\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 74
- fields:
    answer: "A parabola is a set of all points such that the distance to a fixed point\r\
      \n(called the focus) is the same as the distance to a fixed line (called the\r\
      \ndirectrix).\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a parabola\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 75
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.17'
    points: 2
    question: "Sketch the circle\r\n$$(x-5)^2 + (y-1)^2 = 16$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 76
- fields:
    answer: "$$h = -2$$\r\n$$k = -1$$\r\n$$r = \\sqrt{3}$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.17'
    points: 2
    question: "Identify the center and radius of the circle:\r\n$$x^2 + 4x + y^2 +\
      \ 2y + 2 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 77
- fields:
    answer: "$$e = 0.312$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.36'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate the eccentricity of the ellipse:\r\n$$x^2/10000 + y^2/(95^2)\
      \ = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 78
- fields:
    answer: "$$(3, -6)$$\r\n$$y = 4$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.50'
    points: 2
    question: "Identify the focus point and the equation of the directrix for\r\n\
      the parabola:\r\n$$y - 5 = (1/4)(x + 3)^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 79
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2 = 1$$\r\n$$y^2/b^2 = 1 - x^2/a^2$$\r\n$$y^2  = b^2(1\
      \ - x^2/a^2)$$\r\n$$y = \\pm b\\sqrt{1 - x^2/a^2}$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '12.32'
    points: 3
    question: "Show that if $x$ is the $x$-coordinate of a point on an ellipse,\r\n\
      then $y$ can be found from the formula $y = \\pm b \\sqrt{1- x^2/a}$. (The center\r\
      \nis at the origin, the semimajor axis has length $a$ while the semiminor has\r\
      \nlength $b$)\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 80
- fields:
    answer: "If a point is a distance $r$ from $(a, b)$ then\r\n$$r = \\sqrt{ (x-a)^2\
      \ + (y-b)^2 }$$\r\n$$r^2 = (x-a)^2 + (y-b)^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Verify the equation of a circle of radius $r$ centered at $(a, b)$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 81
- fields:
    answer: "The distance of a point $(x, y)$ to the focus $= \\sqrt{ (y - a)^2 +(x-0)^2\
      \ }$.\r\n\r\nThe distance of a point $(x, y)$ to the directrix $=y+a$\r\n\r\n\
      Thus:\r\n\r\n$$y+a = \\sqrt{ (y-a)^2 + x^2 }$$\r\n$$(y+a)^2 = |(y-a)^2 + x^2|\
      \ = (y-a)^2 + x^2$$\r\n$$y^2 + 2ay + a^2 = y^2 -2ay + a^2 + x^2$$\r\n$$4ay \
      \ = x^2$$\r\n$$y  = \\frac{1}{4a}x^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Find the equation for a parabola with focus at $(0, a)$ and directrix\
      \ at line\r\n$y = -a$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 82
- fields:
    answer: "$$(x - a)^2 + (y - b)^2 = r^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give the equation of a circle with center $(a, b)$ and radius $r$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 83
- fields:
    answer: "$$e = \\sqrt{ \\frac{a^2 - b^2}{a^2} }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give a formula for the eccentricity of an ellipse:\r\n$$x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2\
      \ = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 84
- fields:
    answer: "$$(y - k) = \\frac{1}{4a}(x-h)^2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give the formula for a parabola with vertex $(h, k)$ and focus $(h,\
      \ k + a)$:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 85
- fields:
    answer: "If the degree of the polynomial is odd, then it has an even number of\
      \ turning\r\npoints, so it must have one solution since at the tails it points\
      \ opposite\r\nways.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Using the turning point rules, characterize roots of polynomials.\r\
      \n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 86
- fields:
    answer: "1) x = 0, -1, 5/2\r\n2) x = \\pm 2, \\pm 3\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '13.3'
    points: 4
    question: "Solve these equations for the unknown:\r\n\r\n1) $2x^3 - 3x^2 - 5x\
      \ = 0$\r\n\r\n2) $x^4  -13x^2 + 36 = 0$\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 87
- fields:
    answer: "$x = 1, 5, 10$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '13.39'
    points: 4
    question: "Find the solutions to these equations using the rational roots\r\n\
      theorem and synthetic division:\r\n$$x^3-16x^2+65x-50 = 0$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 88
- fields:
    answer: "A polynomial curve of degree $n$ has a maximum of $n-1$ turning points.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: '13.39'
    points: 1
    question: "Characterize the number of turning points of a polynomial in terms\
      \ of the\r\npolynomial degree\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 89
- fields:
    answer: "An even [odd] polynomial will have an odd [even] number of turning points.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What can you say about even and odd polynomials?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 90
- fields:
    answer: "If f is a polynomial with integer coefficients, then each rational root\
      \ can be \r\nexpressed as a fraction in which the numerator is a factor of the\
      \ constant term,\r\nand denominaotr a factor of the leading coefficient.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the rational root theorem\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 91
- fields:
    answer: "A series in which the ratio between two consecutive terms is constant.\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a geometric series\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 92
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\sum_{i = 10}^{30} 2i$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '14.3'
    points: 1
    question: "Write using summation notation the sum of all even numbers from\r\n\
      20 to 60.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 93
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> 4\r\n<li> 2/11\r\n<li> 254\r\n<li> 0 (If $r =\
      \ -1$ then the sum will be 0 if $n$ is even and $a$ if $n$ is odd)\r\n</ol>\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 14.14,17,23,25,28
    points: 6
    question: "Calculate the sums of these series:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $-10\
      \ -7 - 4 - 1 + 2 + 5 + 8 + 11$\r\n<li> $18/100 + 18/10000 + 18/1000000 + \\\
      ldots$\r\n<li> $2 + 4 + 8 + 16 + 32 + 64 + 128$\r\n<li> $1 - 1 + 1 - 1 + 1 -\
      \ 1$\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 97
- fields:
    answer: "If $n$ is even we can pair these as:\r\n$$1 + n$$\r\n$$2 + n-1$$\r\n\
      $$3 + (n-2)$$\r\netc., so that we have $n/2$ pairs, each summing to $n+1$.\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Explain the formula for $\\sum_{i=0}^n i$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 98
- fields:
    answer: "Take\r\n$$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} r^i$$\r\nmultiply by $(r-1)$ and we get:\r\
      \n$$r^n  - 1$$ \r\nso \r\n$$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} ar^i = a \\frac{r^n - 1}{r-1}$$\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Prove the formula for a geometric series\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 99
- fields:
    answer: "$$(n/2)(n+1)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is $\\sum_{i=0}^n i$?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 100
- fields:
    answer: "$$a \\frac{r^n - 1}{r - 1}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the general formula for $$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} ar^i$$?\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 101
- fields:
    answer: "$$n! = n \\times (n-1) \\times (n-2) \\times \\ldots \\times 4 \\times\
      \ 3 \\times 2\r\n\\times 1$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the factorial of a number $n$.\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 102
- fields:
    answer: "Selecting $j$ objects with order from $n$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a permutation of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 103
- fields:
    answer: "Selecting $j$ objects without order from $n$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a combination of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 104
- fields:
    answer: "For n \\in N and any 0 \\le k \\le n, define {n \\choose k} to be the\
      \ number of\r\nk-element subsets of the set {1, 2, ..., n}.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define {n \\choose k}.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 105
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{j!(n-j)!} + \\frac{n!}{(j+1)!(n-j-1)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n!(j+1)}{(j+1)j!(n-j)!}\
      \ + \\frac{n!(n-j)}{(j+1)!(n-j)(n-j-1)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n!(j+1)}{(j+1)!(n-j)!}\
      \ + \\frac{n!(n-j)}{(j+1)!(n-j)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n![j+1+n-j]{(j+1)!(n-j)!}$$\r\
      \n$$ = {n+1 \\choose j + 1}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '15.7'
    points: 3
    question: "Show that ${n \\choose j} + {n \\choose j+1} = {n+1 \\choose j+1}$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 106
- fields:
    answer: "1 4 6 4 1 \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.11'
    points: 2
    question: "If you flip a coin 4 times, there are $2^4$ possible outcomes.\r\n\
      How many of these outcomes have 0 heads? How many have 1 head? 2 heads? 3\r\n\
      heads? 4 heads?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 107
- fields:
    answer: "$$6.35 \\times 10^{11}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.14'
    points: 1
    question: "How many 13-card hands can you draw from a deck of 52 cards?\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 108
- fields:
    answer: "15504\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.15'
    points: 1
    question: " How many ways can you select a 5-member committee from a group\r\n\
      of 20 people?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 109
- fields:
    answer: "$$a^6 + 12a^5 + 60a^4 + 160a^3 + 240a^2 + 192a + 64$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Use the binomial formula to write expressions for $(a + 2)^6$.\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 110
- fields:
    answer: "<ul>\r\n<li>(1, 2, 3)\r\n<li>(2, 1, 3)\r\n<li>(3, 1, 2)\r\n<li>(1, 3,\
      \ 2)\r\n<li>(2, 3, 1)\r\n<li>(3, 2, 1)\r\n</ul>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: Example 2.1.1
    points: 1
    question: "List all the permutations of the set of integers {1, 2,\r\n3}.\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 111
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{(n-j)!}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "How many permutations of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time are there?\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 112
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{j!(n-j)!}$$\r\n\r\nThis is also ${n \\choose j}$.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "How many combinations of $j$ objects from a group of $n$ objects are\
      \ there?\r\nWhat is another name for this?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 113
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a + b)^n = \\sum_{i = 0}^n {n \\choose i}a^ib^{n-i}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Binomial formula\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 114
- fields:
    answer: "Note that you can prove this for various cases of n:\r\n\r\n<ul>\r\n\
      <li>n = 1: a = a\r\n<li>n = 2: a + (a+d) = 2a + d\r\n<li>n = 3: a + (a+d) +\
      \ (a + 2d) = 3a + 3d\r\n</ul>\r\nNote that once you go to n = 4, you can recognize\
      \ a previous term:\r\n\r\n$$a + (a+d) + (a+2d) + (a+3d) = 3a + 3d + a+3d = 4a\
      \ + 6d$$\r\n\r\nThis motivates the idea of doing this sort of substitution generically."
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Explain the motivation behind induction in terms of arithmetic series\
      \ formula.\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 115
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> The formula is true for $n = 1$ since it is $1\
      \ = 1^2$\r\n<li> Assume $S_{2n-1} = n^2.\r\n<li> Then $S_{2(n+1) - 1} = n^2\
      \ + (2n+1) - 1 = (n+1)^2$\r\n</ol>"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '16.5'
    points: 2
    question: "Prove this formula by mathematical induction:\r\n$$1 + 3 +5 + 7 + \\\
      cdots + (2n-1) = n^2$$\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 116
- fields:
    answer: "1 is odd and $1^2$ is odd. Assume $n$ is odd and $n^2$ is odd. The next\
      \ odd\r\nnumber after $n$ is $n+2$. $(n+2)^2 = n^2 +4n+4 = n^2 + 2(2n+2)$. Since\
      \ this is\r\nthe sum of an odd and an even number, it follows that $(n+2)^2$\
      \ is odd.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '16.7'
    points: 4
    question: " Prove that if $n$ is odd, then $n^2$ is odd.\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 117
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> Show that the fact holds for $n = 1$.\r\n<li>\
      \ Next, assume the formula is true for an arbitrary number $j$.\r\n<li> Show\
      \ that *if* the formula is true for the number $j$, then it must also be\r\n\
      true for the number $j+1$.\r\n<li> Once you have completed these steps, then\
      \ the formula has been proved to be\r\ntrue for all whole numbers.\r\n</ol>\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State the method of induction\r\n\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 118
- fields:
    answer: "Think of generational growth\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example of how exponential growth occurs naturally.\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 119
- fields:
    answer: "For negative values $a^{-t} = 1/a^t$.\r\n\r\nwe define $a^{1/q} = \\\
      sqrt[q]{a}$.\r\n\r\nFor rational values:\r\n$$a^{p/q} = a^pa^{1/q}$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Justify an exponential function for negative integers and rational\
      \ values\r\nassuming the definition for positive integers. Note that in this\
      \ level we do not\r\njustify irrational values.\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 120
- fields:
    answer: "$$F(x) = a^x$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an exponential function.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 121
- fields:
    answer: "$$10^{log x} = x$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the common logarithm\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 122
- fields:
    answer: "$$3\\log(x + 4) + \\log(a+b) -2\\log(x-1) - \\log(a^2 + b^2)$$\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '17.36'
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify\r\n$$\\log[ \\frac{(x+4)^3(a+b)}{(x-1)^2(a^2+b^2)}]$$\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 123
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\log(xy)  = \\log(x) + \\log(y)$$\r\n$$\\log(x/y) = \\log(x) - \\\
      log(y)$$\r\n$$\\log(x^n) = n\\log(x)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State the rules of logarithms\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 124
- fields:
    answer: "It means that the planes do not have a common intersection. Either two\
      \ planes\r\nare parallel, or the three intersections of the planes are in three\
      \ parallel\r\nlines.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.1'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 0
    question: "What does it mean geometrically if three equations in three unknowns\
      \ have no solution?\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 125
- fields:
    answer: "It is an equation of the form \r\n$$a_1x_1 + x_2x_2 + \\cdots x_nx_n\
      \ = b$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a linear equation in $n$ variables.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 126
- fields:
    answer: "A system of equations that has [at least one[no] solution is said to\
      \ be\r\n[in]consistent.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an [in]consistent system of equations.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 127
- fields:
    answer: "$$a = 0.7906, b = 80.8837, c = 18.3255$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '18.7'
    points: 3
    question: "Solve this equation systems:\r\n\r\n$$a + b + c = 100$$\r\n$$b = 6\
      \ + 2a + 4c$$\r\n$$c = 12 + 8a$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 128
- fields:
    answer: "$$2x^2 - x - 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '18.13'
    points: 3
    question: "Find a second-degree polynomial that passes through each of\r\nthese\
      \ three points: $(6, 65), (7, 90), (10, 189)$.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 129
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> You can multiply both sides of one of the equations\
      \ by a number.\r\n<li> You can add one equation to another equation.\r\n<li>\
      \ You can add to one equation a multiple of another equation.\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "List legal moves to transform a system of equations\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 130
- fields:
    answer: "Ax = b is defined so that it represents a system of 3 equations in 3\
      \ unknowns\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Motivate the definition of Ax where A is a 3x3 matrix and x is a 3x1\
      \ vector.\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 131
- fields:
    answer: "Multiply both sides by $A^{-1}$:\r\n\r\n$$A^{-1}Ax = A^{-1}d$$\r\n$$Ix\
      \ = A^{-1}d$$\r\n$$x = A^{-1}d$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how to use $A^{-1}$ to solve $Ax = d$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 132
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> $\\det(A^{-1}) = \\frac{1}{det(A)}$\r\n<li> $\\\
      det(AB)     = \\det(AB)$\r\n<li> If $\\det(A) = 0$ then the matrix $A$ has no\
      \ inverse\r\n</ol>"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State 3 properties of determinants:\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 133
- fields:
    answer: "A matrix is a rectangular array of numbers. Two matrices are equal if\
      \ they have the same size and their corresponding entries are equal.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a matrix and when two matrices are equal.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 134
- fields:
    answer: "The coefficients of the $a_ix_i$ terms along with the last column of\
      \ constant\r\nterms in a rectangular array.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the augmented matrix for a system of linear equations\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 135
- fields:
    answer: "The zero matrix an array of all zeros. For addition first note that the\
      \ matrices need to have the same dimensions. Then you just add component wise\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.1'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the zero matrix. Define addition of matrices\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 136
- fields:
    answer: "Multiply each element of the array by that scalar.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the multiplication of a matrix by a scalar.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 137
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> start with the first row of A and the first column\
      \ of B.\r\n<li> multiply the corresponding elements of this row and column\r\
      \n<li> Add all the products together, and the result is the entry in the first\
      \ row\r\nand column of AB.\r\n<li> Repeat this process to find each element\
      \ of AB, using the ith row of A and\r\nthe jth columbn of B to get the element\
      \ in the ith row and jth column of AB.\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Define matrix multiplication: $AB$ (where the number of columns of\
      \ A equals the\r\nnumber of rows of B).\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 138
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} a_1 b_1 c_1 \\\\ a_2 b_2 c_2 \\\\ a_3 b_3 c_3\
      \ \\\\\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$ = a_1b_2c_3 + a_2b_3c_1 + a_3b_1c_2 - a_3b_2c_1\
      \ - a_2b_1c_3 - a_1b_3c_2$$"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the determinant of a 3x3 matrix\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 139
- fields:
    answer: "No: \r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 6 & 12 \\\\ 4 & 2 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 11 & 6 \\\\ 1 & 7 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\nThen\
      \ \r\n$$AB = \\begin{pmatrix} 78 & 120 \\\\ 46 & 38 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\
      $$BA = \\begin{pmatrix} 90 & 144 \\\\ 34 & 26 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: E
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Is matrix multiplication commutative? If so prove it, if not give a\r\
      \ncounterexample.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 140
- fields:
    answer: "$$A + B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    -2 & 4 & 5 & 4 \\\\ 1 & 2 & 2 & 3 \\\
      \\ 7 & 0 & 3 & 5 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$A - B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\
      \n    6 & -2 & -5 & 2 \\\\ -3 & -2 & 2 & 5 \\\\ 1 & -4 & 11 & -5 \r\n      \
      \    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$2A    = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    4 & 2 & 0 & 6 \\\\\
      \ -2 & 0 & 4 & 8 \\\\ 8 & -4 & 14 & 0 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$-\\\
      frac{1}{2}B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    2 & -3/2 & -5/2 & -1/2 \\\\ -1 & -1 &\
      \ 0 & 1/2 \\\\ -3/2 & -1 & 2 & -5/2 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: Eg 1.3.3-4
    points: 3
    question: "For the matrices\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2 & 1 & 0 & 3 \\\\ -1 &\
      \ 0 & 2 & 4 \\\\ 4 & -2 & 7 & 0 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} -4\
      \ & 3 & 5 & 1 \\\\ 2 & 2 & 0 & -1 \\\\ 3 & 2 & -4 & 5\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\
      Compute: $A + B$, $A - B$, $2A$, $(-\\frac{1}{2}B$:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 141
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\begin{pmatrix} 132 & 92 \\\\ 92 & 62 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} $$\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.3'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 4 & 12 \\\\ 4 & 7 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}\
      \ \\cdot\r\n  \\begin{pmatrix} 9 & 5 \\\\ 8 & 6 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 142
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 6, y = 10, z = 4$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Downing 19.21: Use the matrix triangularization process to solve:\r\
      \n$$6x + 3y + 8z = 98$$\r\n$$5x + 11y - 9z = 104$$\r\n$$7x - 12y - 9z  -1144$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 143
- fields:
    answer: "$$0$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.33'
    points: 1
    question: "Calculate the determinant of \r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 6 & 11 \\\\\
      \ 12 & 22 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 144
- fields:
    answer: "No:\r\n\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 2 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 1 \\\\ 3 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$C = \\begin{pmatrix}\
      \ 2 & 5 \\\\ 3 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\nThen $AB = AC$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: E
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.3
    points: 2
    question: "Does the cancellation law hold for Matrices? If so prove\r\nit, if\
      \ not give a counterexample.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 145
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} a & b \\\\ c & d \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} = ad -\
      \ bc$$\r\n$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} b & a \\\\ d & c \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} = bc\
      \ - ad$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '19.45'
    points: 3
    question: "Prove that for 2x2 matrices if you interchange two columns of\r\nthe\
      \ determinant, then the value of determinant changes sign.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 146
- fields:
    answer: "If $I$ is an identity matrix and $A$ is any other matrix with the same\
      \ number\r\nof rows as $I$, then $IA = A.$ Alsi if $B$ has the same number of\
      \ columns as\r\n$I$ then $BI = B$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Identity Matrix Property\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 147
- fields:
    answer: "Let $A_i$ represent replacing the $ith$ column of $A$ with the column\
      \ vector\r\n$d$.\r\n$$x = \\frac{ \\det(A_1) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n$$y = \\frac{\
      \ \\det(A_2) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n$$z = \\frac{ \\det(A_3) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State how to solve a 3x3 system using determinants:\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 148
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li>  $A + B = B + A$\r\n<li>  $A + (B + C) = (A+B)\
      \ + C$\r\n<li>  $A(BC) = (AB)C$\r\n<li>  $A(B + C) = AB + AC$\r\n<li>  $(B+C)A\
      \ = BA + CA$\r\n<li>  $A(B-C) = AB - AC$\r\n<li>  $(B-C)A = BA - CA$\r\n<li>\
      \  $a(B+C) = aB + aC$\r\n<li>  $a(B-C) = aB - aC$\r\n<li> $(a+b)C = aC + bC$\r\
      \n<li> $(a-b)C = aC - bC$\r\n<li> $a(bC)  = (ab)C$\r\n<li> $a(BC)  = (aB)C =\
      \ B(aC)$\r\n<li> $A + 0 = 0 + A = A$\r\n<li> $A - A = 0$\r\n<li> $A0 = 0$ and\
      \ $0A = 0$ (not $A0 = 0 = 0A$).\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.1
    points: 4
    question: "State the basic properties of arthmetic of Matrices over\r\nthe reals.\
      \ (hint there are 16)\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 149
- fields:
    answer: "A^{-1} = 1/det(A) [ d -b]\r\n                  [-c  a]\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Give the formula for the inverse of a 2x2 matrix in terms of determinants.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 150
- fields:
    answer: "Considering quadratics where $b^2 - 4ac < 0$ such as $x^2 + x + 1 = 0$\r\
      \nnaturally leads to solutions where $\\sqrt{-1}$ needs to be considered."
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example that leads us to imaginary numbers\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 151
- fields:
    answer: "Considering a complex number $a + bi$ (where $a$ and $b$ are real), we\
      \ can plot\r\nthis number on the x-y plane by the coordinates $(a, b)$."
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the idea behind the complex plane.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 152
- fields:
    answer: "By using the idea that $a + bi$ is a point on the complex plane, we note\
      \ that\r\nthe length of the vector from the origin to this point is $\\sqrt{a^2\
      \ + b^2}$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Motivate the definition of the absolute value of a complex number\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 153
- fields:
    answer: "An imaginary number is a multiple of $i = \\sqrt{-1}$. Thus $ai = \\\
      sqrt{-a^2}$. A complex number is A real number plus an imaginary number. The\
      \ real number is called the real part\r\nand the imaginary number is called\
      \ the imaginary part.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define imaginary and complex numbers.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 154
- fields:
    answer: "a + bi = c + di if a = c and b = d\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define when two complex numbers are equal.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 155
- fields:
    answer: "$$|a + bi| = \\sqrt{a^2 + b^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the absolute value (or modulus) of a complex number\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 156
- fields:
    answer: "$$41 + 129i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.14'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate \r\n$$(4 + 11i)(6-2i) + (3 + 5i)(10 + 7i)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 157
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = -4 \\pm 3i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.14'
    points: 2
    question: "Find the solution to \r\n$$x^2 + 8x + 25 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 158
- fields:
    answer: "$$6/5 + (9/10)i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.59'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify \r\n$$\\frac{ 3 + 6i }{ 4 + 2i }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 159
- fields:
    answer: "$$i - 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.64'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $z$\r\n\r\n$$(i+1)z = -2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 160
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.1.1
    points: 1
    question: "Plot the point given below:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> 2 + 3i\r\n<li>\
      \ -4\r\n<li> -3-2i\r\n<li> -5i\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 161
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n|z| = 5\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.2
    points: 1
    question: "Find |z| if z = 3 - 4i\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 162
- fields:
    answer: "if z = a+bi then\r\n\r\nzz^* = (a+bi)(a-bi)\r\n     = a^2 -b^2i^2\r\n\
      \     = a^2 + b^2\r\n     = |z|^2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.1
    points: 1
    question: "Prove that $zz^* = |z|^2$ for any complex number $z$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 163
- fields:
    answer: "$z = 1/|z_2|^2 \\cdot z_1z_2^*$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.2
    points: 1
    question: "If $z_2 \\ne 0$, then what is the solution of $z_1 = z_2z$, given $z_1$\
      \ and $z_2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 164
- fields:
    answer: "1) (z_1 + z_2)^* = z_1^* + z_2^*\r\n2) (z_1 - z_2)^* = z_1^* - z_2^*\r\
      \n3) (z_1z_2)^* = z_1^*z_2^*\r\n4) (z_1/z_2)^* = z_1^*/z_2^*\r\n5) z^*^* = z\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.3
    points: 3
    question: "For any complex numbers $z$, $z_1$ and $z_2$, state 5\r\nproperties\
      \ of the complex conjugate.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 165
- fields:
    answer: "Vectors can be represented geometrically as directed line segments or\
      \ arrows in\r\n2- or 3-space. The tail of the arrow is called the initial point\
      \ and then tip\r\nof the arrow is called the terminal point."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [1]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how a vector is represented and use the terms initial point\
      \ and terminal\r\npoint."
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 166
- fields:
    answer: "$v + w$: Position the vector $w$ so that its initial point concides with\
      \ the\r\nterminal point of $v$. The vector $v+w$ has initial point the same\
      \ as $v$ and\r\nterminal point of $w$ as so positioned. Then we define the negative\
      \ - $-v$: The vector whose terminal point is the initial point of $v$ and whose\r\
      \ninitial point is the terminal point of $v$. Finally using these two definitions,\
      \ the difference: $v - w = v + (-w)$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: [1]
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: Define the sum and difference of two vectors geometrically.
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 167
- fields:
    answer: "$$|u| = \\sqrt{v_1^2 + v_2^2 + v_3^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: [6]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the length (or norm) of a vector $v = (v_1, v_2, v_3)$ in 3-space.\r\
      \n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 168
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\sqrt{ (u_1 - v_1)^2 + (u_2 - v_2)^2 + (u_3 - v_3)^2 }$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: D
    concepts: [8]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the distance between two vectors $(u_1, u_2, u_3)$ and $(v_1,\
      \ v_2, v_3)$\r\nin 3-space.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 169
- fields:
    answer: "$$u \\cdot v = |u||v| \\cos \\theta.$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: D
    concepts: [1, 6]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the dot product of two 2- or 3-vectors where $\\theta$ is the\
      \ angle\r\nbetween u and v."
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 170
- fields:
    answer: "$$v = (7 - 2, 5 - (-1), (-8) - 4) = (5, 6, -12)$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: P
    concepts: [3]
    index: Example 3.1.2
    points: 1
    question: "Give the components of the vector $v = \\arrow{P_1P_2}$\r\nwith initial\
      \ point $(2, -1, 4)$ and terminal point $(7, 5, -8)$.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 171
- fields:
    answer: "$$(2, -1, 1) \\cdot (1, 1, 2) = 2 - 1 + 2 = 3$$\r\n$$= |(2, -1, 1)||(1,\
      \ 1, 2)| \\cos \\theta$$\r\nSo,\r\n$$\\frac{ 3 }{ \\sqrt{6}\\sqrt{6} } = \\\
      cos \\theta$$\r\n$$\\theta = \\pi/3$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: X
    concepts: [1, 8]
    index: Eg 3.2.2
    points: 2
    question: "Consider the vectors (2, -1, 1) and $(1, 1, 2)$ and find\r\nthe angle\
      \ between them."
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 172
- fields:
    answer: "The set of points $p$ is the set of points on the sphere of radius 1\
      \ whose\r\ncenter is at the point $p_0$."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: X
    concepts: [7]
    index: 3.2.8
    points: 1
    question: "Let $p_0 = (x_0, y_0, z_0)$ and $p = (x, y, z)$. Describe the set\r\
      \nof all points $p$ for which $|p - p_0| = 1$."
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 173
- fields:
    answer: "$$p = tq$$\r\n$$(2, k) = (3t, 5t)$$\r\n$$t = 2/3$$\r\n$$p = (2, 10/3)$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: X
    concepts: [1, 9]
    index: 3.3.14
    points: 2
    question: "Let $p = (2, k)$ and $q = (3, 5)$ Find $k$ such that \r\n$p$ and $q$\
      \ are parallel.\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 174
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a, b, c) \\cdot (x, y, z) = (ax, by, cz)$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: S
    concepts: [1, 7]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State, without proof, the simplified formula for the dot product (that\
      \ is the\r\nformula in terms of components, not in terms of angles.)\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 175
- fields:
    answer: "Select a point O, called the origin. and choose three mutually perpendicular\r\
      \nlines, called coordinate axes, passing through the origin. Label these axis\r\
      \n$x$, $y$, and $z$. and select a positive direction for each coordinate axis."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [3]
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to construct a rectangular coordinate system to describe\
      \ vectors in\r\n3-space.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 176
- fields:
    answer: "A right-handed system has the property that an ordinary screw pointed\
      \ in the\r\npositive direction on the z-axis would be advanced if the positive\
      \ $x$-axis is\r\nrotated 90 degrees toward the positive $y$-axis. \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [3]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the difference between a left-handed versus right-handed coordinate\r\
      \nsystem.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 177
- fields:
    answer: "Suppose we have translated the axes of an $xy$-coordinate system to obtain\
      \ a \r\n$x'y'$-coordinate system whose origin $O'$ is at the point $(x, y) =\
      \ (k, l)$.\r\n\r\nA point $(x, y)$ has coordinates \r\n$$x' = x - k,\\ y = y\
      \ - l$$\r\nin the $x'y'$-system. These equations are called the translation\
      \ equations.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [4]
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain coordinate translation.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 178
- fields:
    answer: "$$| \\frac{v}{|v|} | = \\frac{ |v| }{ |v| }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: X
    concepts: [7]
    index: 3.2.6a
    points: 1
    question: "Show that if v is a nonzero vector then \r\n$$\\frac{1}{|v|}v$$\r\n\
      is a unit vector. \r\n\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 179
- fields:
    answer: "When the dot product is zero. \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: D
    concepts: [1, 9]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define orthogonal vectors\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 180
- fields:
    answer: "$$proj_a u = \\frac{u \\cdot a}{|u|^2} a$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: D
    concepts: [1, 2]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the orthogonal projection of u on a.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 181
- fields:
    answer: "$$u - proj_a u = u - \\frac{u \\cdot a}{|u|^2} a$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: D
    concepts: [2]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the vector component of u orthogonal to a.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 182
- fields:
    answer: "$$u \\cdot a = 15$$\r\n$$|a|^2 = 21$$\r\n\r\n$$\\proj_a u = (20/7, -5/7,\
      \ 10/7)$$\r\n$$u - \\proj_a u = (-6/7, -2/7, 11/7)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: X
    concepts: [2]
    index: Eg 3.3.6
    points: 2
    question: "Let $u = (2, -1, 3)$ and $a = (4, -1, 2)$. Find the vector\r\ncomponent\
      \ of $a$ along $a$ and the vector component of $u$ orthogonal to $a$.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 183
- fields:
    answer: "No. For example $a = (0, 1)$, $b = (1, 1)$ and $c = (-1, 1)$.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: E
    concepts: [1, 9]
    index: Eg 3.3.13
    points: 1
    question: "Suppose that $a \\cdot b = a \\cdot c$ and $a \\ne 0$. Does it\r\n\
      follow that $b = c$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 184
- fields:
    answer: "Let $\\theta$ be the angle between $(1, 1, 1)$ and $(1, 1, 0)$.\r\n\r\
      \n$$\\cos \\theta = \\frac{ (1, 1, 1)\\cdot(1, 1, 0) }{ |(1, 1, 1)||(1, 1, 0|\
      \ }$$\r\n$$ = \\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}\\sqrt{2}}$$\r\n$$\\theta \\approx 35.26$$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: X
    concepts: [1, 8]
    index: 3.3.18
    points: 4
    question: "Find the angle between a diagonal of a cube and one of its faces.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 185
- fields:
    answer: "Let $u = (a, b, c)$ and $v = (x, y, z)$ be two nonzero vectors with terminal\r\
      \npoints $P$ and $Q$ respectively. If $\\theta$ is the angle between them then\
      \ the law of cosines (from High School Geometry) states:\r\n$$|PQ|^2 = |u|^2\
      \ + |v|^2 - 2|u||v| \\cos \\theta$$\r\n\r\nSince $PQ = v - u$, we can write:\r\
      \n$$|u||v|\\cos \\theta = \\frac{1}{2} (|u|^2 + |v|^2 - |v-u|^2)$$\r\n$$u \\\
      cdot v         = \\frac{1}{2} (|u|^2 + |v|^2 - |v-u|^2)$$\r\nUsing the definition\
      \ of norm:\r\n$$u \\cdot v         = \\frac{1}{2} (a^2 + b^2 + c^2 + x^2 + y^2\
      \ + z^2 \r\n    - (a-x)^2 + (b-y)^2 + (c-z)^2)$$\r\n$$u \\cdot v         = \\\
      frac{1}{2} ( -2ax - 2by - 2cz)$$\r\n$$                  = ax + by + cz$$\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: P
    concepts: [1, 7]
    index: ''
    points: 4
    question: "Prove the High School statement that the dot product of 3-vectors as\
      \ defined in\r\nterms of the angle between vectors $\\theta$ is equal to the\
      \ sum of the product\r\nof the components.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 186
- fields:
    answer: "1) $u \\cdot v = v \\cdot u$\r\n2) $u \\cdot (v + w) = u \\cdot v + u\
      \ \\cdot w$\r\n3) $k(u \\cdot v) = (ku) \\cdot v = u \\cdot (kv)$\r\n4) $v \\\
      cdot v > 0$ if $v \\ne 0$ and $v \\cdot v = 0$ if $v = 0$."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: Thm 3.3.2
    points: 2
    question: "If u, v and w are 2- or 3-space and k is a scalar then\r\nstate the\
      \ basic properties of the dot product.\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 187
- fields:
    answer: "1) $u + v = v + u$\r\n2) $u + 0 = 0 + u = u$\r\n3) $k(lu) = (kl)u$\r\n\
      4) $(k+l)u = ku + lu$\r\n5) $(u + v) + w = u + (v + w)$\r\n6) $u + (-u) = 0$\r\
      \n7) $k(u + v) = ku + kv$\r\n8) $1u = u$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: Thm 3.2.1
    points: 2
    question: "If u, v, and w are vectors in 2- or 3-space and k and l\r\nare scalars\
      \ give the basic properties.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 188
- fields:
    answer: "Since the three points lie in a plane, we can write:\r\n$$a + 2b - c\
      \ + d = 0$$\r\n$$2a + 3b + c + d = 0$$\r\n$$3a - b + 2c + d = 0$$\r\n\r\nSolving\
      \ this system (using techniques from High School Algebra) we get \r\n$$a = -9/16t,\\\
      \ v = 1/16t,\\ c = 5/16t\\ d = t$$\r\nSo letting $t = 16$, \r\n$$9x + y - 5z\
      \ - 16 = 0$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.2
    points: 4
    question: "Find the equation of the plane passing through the points\r\n$(1, 2,\
      \ -1)$, $(2, 3, 1)$, and $(3, 1, -2)$."
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 189
- fields:
    answer: "Since $(3, -4, 8)$ is parallel to $l$ and $(2, 4, -1)$ lies on $l$, the\
      \ line\r\n$l$ is given by\r\n$$(x, y, z) = (2, 4, -1) + t(3, -4, 8)$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.5a
    points: 2
    question: "Find parametetric equations for the line $l$ passing\r\nthrough the\
      \ points $(2, 4, -1)$ and $(5, 0, 7)$."
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 190
- fields:
    answer: "The equation for the plane through $a = (3, -6, 7)$ perpendicular to\
      \ $n = (5,\r\n-2, 1)$ is\r\n\r\n$$n \\cdot (x - a) = 0$$\r\n\r\n$$5x_1 - 2x_2\
      \ + x_3 = 34$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.21
    points: 1
    question: "Find an equation for the plane that passes through the\r\npoint $(3,\
      \ -6, 7)$ and is parallel to the plane $5x - 2y + z - 5 = 0$."
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 191
- fields:
    answer: "Let these four points be $p_0, p_1, p_2$, and $p_4$.\r\n\r\nThe vector\
      \ from $p_0$ to $p_1$ is $(-1, 2, 4)$\r\nThe vector from $p_0$ to $p_2$ is $(-3,\
      \ 1, 2)$\r\n\r\nSince the vector from $p_0$ to $p_3$ $(3, 2, 4)$ is of the form\
      \ \r\n$$s(-1, 2, 4) + t(-3, 1, 2) = (3, 2, 4)$$\r\n\r\nSolving these three equations\
      \ we get $t = -8/5$ and $s = 9/5$.\r\n\r\nThus the 4 points lie in the same\
      \ plane."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.25
    points: 4
    question: "Show that the points $(-1, -2, -3)$, $(-2, 0, 1)$, $(-4,\r\n-1, -1)$,\
      \ and $(2, 0, 1)$ lie in the same plane."
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 192
- fields:
    answer: "The angle $\\theta$ between the line and the normal to the plane satisfies\r\
      \n$$\\cos \\theta = \\frac{ (1, -2, -3) \\cdot (1, -1, -3) } \r\n    { |(1,\
      \ -2, -3)| |(1, -1, -3)| }$$\r\n$$ = \\frac{12}{\\sqrt{14}\\sqrt{11}}$$\r\n\r\
      \nSo $\\theta = 14.76$\r\n\r\nHence the angle between the line and the plane\
      \ is $90 - \\theta \\approx 75$."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.45
    points: 4
    question: "Find the acute angle of intersection between the plane\r\n$x - y -\
      \ 3z = 5$ and the line $x = 2 - t,\\ y = 2t,\\ z = 3t - 1$ to the nearest\r\n\
      degree.\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 193
- fields:
    answer: "By hypothesis, not all $a$, $b$ and $c$ are zero. Suppose that $a \\\
      ne 0$. Then\r\nwe can write\r\n$$a(x + d/a)) + by + cz = 0$$\r\nwhich is the\
      \ point-normal form of the plane. \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.1
    points: 2
    question: "Prove that the general form of a plane defines, in fact, a\r\nplane.\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 194
- fields:
    answer: "Let $Q(x_1, y_1, z_1)$ be any point in the plane. Position the normal\
      \ $n = (a,\r\nb, c)$ so that its initial point is at $Q$. The the distance $D$\
      \ is equal to\r\nthe length of the orthogonal projection of $QP_0$ on $n$. Thus\
      \ from\r\nAnton 3.1/3.2:\r\n\r\n$$D = | \\proj_a QP_0| = \\frac{ |QP_0 \\cdot\
      \ n| }{ |n| }$$\r\n\r\nBut,\r\n$$QP_0 = (x_0 - x_1, y_0 - y_1, z_0 - z_1)$$\r\
      \n$$QP_0 \\cdot n = a(x_0 - x_1) + b(y_0 - y_1) + c(z_0 - z_1)$$\r\n$$|n| =\
      \ \\sqrt{a^2 + b^2 + c^2}$$\r\n\r\nThus by substituting these values in the\
      \ formula above, we get:\r\n\r\n$$D = \\frac{ |a(x_0 - x_1) + b(y_0 - y_1) +\
      \ c(z_0 - z_1)| }\r\n    { \\sqrt{a^2 + b^2 + c^2 } }$$\r\n\r\nSince $Q$ lies\
      \ in the plane, its coordinates satisfy the equation of the plane,\r\nthus:\r\
      \n$$ax_1 + by_1 + cz_1 + d = 0$$\r\nor\r\n$$d = -ax_1 - by_1 - cz_1$$\r\n\r\n\
      Substituting this into the above we get the distance formula.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 7
    question: "Prove the distance formula for the distance between a point and a plane.\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 195
- fields:
    answer: "$$a(x - x_0) + b(y - y_0) + c(z - z_0) = 0$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the point-normal form of the equation of a plane for a plane\
      \ going\r\nthrough $(x_0, y_0, z_0)$ with normal vector $(a, b, c)$.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 196
- fields:
    answer: "If $(a, b, c)$ is the normal (not zero) for the plane then the general\
      \ equation\r\nis:\r\n\r\n$$ax + by + cz + d = 0$$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.1
    points: 1
    question: "State the general form of the equation of a plane.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 197
- fields:
    answer: "Let $(x_0, y_0, z_0)$ be a point on the plane and suppose the plane is\
      \ parallel\r\nto $(a, b, c)$. Then\r\n$$(x, y, z) = (x_0, y_0, z_0) + t(a, b,\
      \ c)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the parametric equations for a plane.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 198
- fields:
    answer: "$$D = \\frac{ |ax_0 + by_0 + cz_0 + d| }{ \\sqrt{ a^2 + b^2 + c^2 } }$$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the formula for the distance between a point $(x_0, y_0, z_0)$\
      \ and the\r\nplane in general form: $ax + by + cz + d = 0$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 199
- fields:
    answer: "The product $Ax$ is a linear combination of the column matrices of $A$\
      \ with\r\ncoefficients coming from the matrix $x$. \r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain $Ax$ in terms of linear combinations\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 200
- fields:
    answer: "1. Multiply a row by a nonzero constant.\r\n2. Interchange two rows.\r\
      \n3. Add a multiple of one row to another row.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the elementary row operations.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 201
- fields:
    answer: "To be in row-echelon form:\r\n1. if a row does not consist entirely of\
      \ zeros, then the first nonzero number\r\nin the row is a 1.\r\n2. If there\
      \ are any rows that consist entirely of zeros, then they are grouped\r\ntogether\
      \ at the bottom of the matrix.\r\n3. In any two sucessive rows that are not\
      \ all zero, the leading 1 in the lower\r\nrow occurs farther to the right than\
      \ the leading 1 in the higher row.\r\n\r\nTo be in reduced row-echelon form\
      \ 1-3 must hold, as well as:\r\n4. Each column that contains a leading 1 has\
      \ zeroes everywhere else.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Define [reduced] row-echelon form.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 202
- fields:
    answer: "All the constant terms are zero.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a homogeneous system of linear equations.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 203
- fields:
    answer: "$$x_1 = 3,\\ x_2 = 1,\\ x_3 = 2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.2.6a
    points: 2
    question: "Solve this system by Gauss-Jordan Elminiation:\r\n$$x_1 + x_2 + 2x_3\
      \ = 8$$\r\n$$-x_1 - 2x_2 + 3x_3 = 1$$\r\n$$3x_1 - 7x_2 + 4x_3 = 10$$\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 204
- fields:
    answer: "$$AB = \\begin{pmatrix} 67 & 41 & 41 \\\\ 64 & 21 & 59 \\\\ 63 & 67 &\
      \ 57\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 67 \\\\ 64 \\\\ 63 \\end{pmatrix}\
      \ =\r\n   6\\begin{pmatrix} 3 \\\\ 6 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   0\\begin{pmatrix}\
      \ -2\\\\ 5 \\\\ 4 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   7\\begin{pmatrix} 7 \\\\ 4 \\\\\
      \ 9 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 41 \\\\ 21 \\\\ 67 \\end{pmatrix}\
      \ =\r\n  -2\\begin{pmatrix} 3 \\\\ 6 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   1\\begin{pmatrix}\
      \ -2\\\\ 5 \\\\ 4 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   7\\begin{pmatrix} 7 \\\\ 4 \\\\\
      \ 9 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 41 \\\\ 59 \\\\ 57 \\end{pmatrix}\
      \ =\r\n   4\\begin{pmatrix} 3 \\\\ 6 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   3\\begin{pmatrix}\
      \ -2\\\\ 5 \\\\ 4 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}\r\n   5\\begin{pmatrix} 7 \\\\ 4 \\\\\
      \ 9 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.3.8
    points: 2
    question: "Let \r\n\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 3 & -2 & 7 \\\\ 6 & 5 & 4 \\\\ 0\
      \ & 4 & 9 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 6 & -2 & 4 \\\\ 0 & 1 7\
      \ 3 \\\\ 7 & 7 & 5 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\nThen express each row matrix of $AB$\
      \ as a linear combination of the column\r\nmatrices of $A$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 205
- fields:
    answer: "Possible terminal points are of the form \r\n$$(-1, 3, -5) + t(6, 7,\
      \ -3)$$\r\nwhere $t < 0.$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.1.4b
    points: 1
    question: Find a nonzero vector ${\bf u}$ with initial point $P(-1, 3, -5)$ such
      that ${\bf u}$ is oppositely directed to ${\bf v}  = (6, 7, -3)$
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 206
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{1}{4} \\| {\\bf u} + {\\bf v} \\|^2 - \\frac{1}{4} \\|{\\bf\
      \ u} - {\\bf v} \\|^2 = \\frac{1}{4}({\\bf u} + {\\bf v}) \\cdot ({\\bf u} +\
      \ {\\bf v}) - \\frac{1}{4}({\\bf u} - {\\bf v}) \\cdot ({\\bf u} - {\\bf v})$$\r\
      \n$$ = \\frac{1}{4} {\\bf u} \\cdot {\\bf u} + \\frac{1}{2} {\\bf u} \\cdot\
      \ {\\bf v} + \\frac{1}{4} {\\bf v} \\cdot {\\bf v} - \\frac{1}{4} {\\bf u} \\\
      cdot {\\bf u} + \\frac{1}{2} {\\bf u} \\cdot {\\bf v} - \\frac{1}{4} {\\bf v}\
      \ \\cdot {\\bf v}$$\r\n= {\\bf u} \\cdot {\\bf v}$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.3.17
    points: 3
    question: Establish the identity $$\|{\bf u} + {\bf v}\|^2 + \| {\bf u} - {\bf
      v} \|^2 = 2\| {\bf u} |^2 + 2\| {\bf v} \|^2.$$
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 207
- fields:
    answer: "They intersect because the system of 3 equations in 2 unknowns:\r\n$$3\
      \ + 4t = -1 + 12s$$\r\n$$4 + t = 7 + 6s$$\r\n$$1 = 5 + 3s$$\r\nhas a solution,\
      \ namely $s = -\\frac{4}{3},\\ t = -5$. The intersection is \r\n$$(x, y, z)\
      \ = (-17, -1, 1)$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 3.5.35
    points: 2
    question: "Show that the line\r\n$$ x - 3=4t,\\ y - 4 = t,\\ z - 1 = 0\\ (-\\\
      infty < t < +\\infty)$$\r\nand\r\n$$x + 1 = 12t,\\ y - 7 = 6t,\\ z - 5 = 3t,\\\
      \ (-\\infty < t < +\\infty)$$\r\nintersect and find the point of intersection."
    section: 3
  model: core.question
  pk: 208
- fields:
    answer: "If $Ax = b$ is a system of linear equations, exactly on one of 1) The\
      \ system\r\nhas no solutions, 2) one solution, or 3) more than one solution.\r\
      \n\r\nThus we need to show that if there is more than one solution there are\r\
      \ninfinitely many solutions.\r\n\r\nLet $x_1$ and $x_2$ be two such solutions\
      \ to $Ax = b$.\r\nThen we can form $x_0 = x_1 - x_2$ where $x_0$ is not zero\
      \ because the $x_i$\r\nare distinct. Then:\r\n$$Ax_0 = A(x_1 - x_2) = 0 - 0\
      \ = 0$$\r\n\r\nFurther, if we let $k$ be any scalar:\r\n$$A(x_1 + kx_0) = b\
      \ + k0 = b$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.6'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.6.1
    points: 2
    question: "Prove that every linear system has either no, one or\r\ninfinitely\
      \ many solutions."
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 209
- fields:
    answer: "Gaussian Elimination:\r\n1. Locate the leftmost column that does not\
      \ entirely consist of zeros.\r\n2. Interchange the top row with another row,\
      \ if necessary, to bring a nonzero\r\nentry to the top of the column found in\
      \ step 1.\r\n3. If the entry that is now at the top of the column found in Step\
      \ 1 is $a$,\r\nmultiply the first row by $1/a$ in order to introduce a leading\
      \ 1.\r\n4. Add suitable multiples of the top row to the rows below so that all\
      \ entries\r\nbelow the leading 1 become zeros.\r\n5. Now cover the top row in\
      \ the matrix and begin again with Step 1 applied to\r\nthe submatrix that remains.\
      \ Continue in this way until the entire matrix is in\r\nrow-echelon form.\r\n\
      \r\nGauss-Jordan Elimination:\r\n6. Beginning with the last nonzero row and\
      \ working upward, add suitable\r\nmultiplies of each row to the rows above to\
      \ introduce zeros above the leading\r\n1's.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: State the Gaussian[-Jordan] Elimination procedure.
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 210
- fields:
    answer: "A homogeneous system of linear equations with more unknowns than equations\
      \ has\r\ninfinitely many solutions.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.2.1
    points: 1
    question: "State the theorem on linear systems with more unknowns than equations.\r\
      \n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 211
- fields:
    answer: "If $R$ is the reduced row-echelon form of a *square* matrix $A$, then\
      \ either\r\n$R$ has a row of zeros or $R$ is the identity matrix.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.3
    points: 1
    question: "Characterize the reduced row-echelon form of a matrix in\r\nterms of\
      \ zeros and ones.\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 212
- fields:
    answer: "Every system of linear equations has either no solutions, exactly one\
      \ solution\r\nor infinitely many solutions.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.6'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.6.1
    points: 1
    question: " State the theorem on number of solutions of a linear\r\nsystem.\r\n"
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 213
- fields:
    answer: If the $i$th row of $A$ is a row of zeros, then the $i$th row of $AB$
      is a row of zeros. To see this recall that the $i$th row of $AB$ is a linear
      combination of the rows $B_{j}$ the coefficients in this linear combination
      are the entries (all zero) in the $i$th row of $A$.
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.3.8
    points: 1
    question: Show that if $A$ has a row of zeros and $B$ is any matrix for which
      $AB$ is defined, then $AB$ also has a row of zeros
    section: 5
  model: core.question
  pk: 214
- fields:
    answer: "To find the inverse of an invertible matrix $A$, we must find a sequence\
      \ of\r\nelementary row operations that reduces $A$ to the identity and then\
      \ perform\r\nthis same sequence of operations on $I_n$ to obtain $A^{-1}$.\r\
      \n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: '1.4'
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how to find the inverse of a matrix using elementary matrices.\r\
      \n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 215
- fields:
    answer: "Suppose that $B$ and $C$ are inverses of $A$. Then\r\n$$BA  = I$$\r\n\
      $$BAC = C$$\r\n$$BI  = C$$\r\n$$B   = C$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.4
    points: 1
    question: "Prove that inverses are unique.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 216
- fields:
    answer: "$AB$ is invertible with inverse $B^{-1}A^{-1}$.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.6
    points: 1
    question: "If $A$ and $B$ are inveritble matrices of the same size, then what\
      \ can you say\r\nabout $AB$?\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 217
- fields:
    answer: "By the theorem from the statement section (Anton 1.5.3) $A$ is invertible\
      \ if\r\n$Ax = 0$ has only the trivial solution.\r\n\r\nLet $x_0$ be any solution\
      \ of $Ax = 0$. Then\r\n$$BAx_0 = 0$$\r\n$$Ix_0 = 0$$\r\n$$x_0 = 0$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.6'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.6.3
    points: 2
    question: "Prove that if $A$ and $B$ are square matrices such that\r\n$BA = I$,\
      \ then $A$ is invertible.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 218
- fields:
    answer: "$$BA = I$$\r\n$$BAA^{-1} = A^{-1}$$\r\n$$B = A^{-1}$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.6'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.6.3
    points: 1
    question: "Prove that if $A$ and $B$ are square matrices such that\r\n$BA = I$,\
      \ then not only is $A$ invertible, but $B = A^{-1}$.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 219
- fields:
    answer: "If $A$ is a square matrix and if there exists a square matrix $B$ of\
      \ the same\r\nsize such that $AB = BA = I$ then $A$ is said to be invertible\
      \ with inverse\r\n$B$.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define when a matrix is invertible.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 220
- fields:
    answer: "An $n \\times n$ matrix is called an elementary matrix if it can be obtained\r\
      \nfrom the $n \\times n$ identity matrix $I_n$ by performing a single elementary\r\
      \nrow operation."
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an elementary matrix.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 221
- fields:
    answer: "Matrices are row equivalent if they can be obtained from one another\
      \ by a\r\nfinite sequence of elementary row operations.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define row equivalent matrices.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 222
- fields:
    answer: "$$E_1 = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 1 & 0 \\\\ 1 & 0 & 0 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$E_2 = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 1 & 0 \\\\ 1 & 0 & 0 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.5.3a
    points: 2
    question: "Find an elementary matrices $E_1$ and $E_2$ such that $E_1A = B$\r\n\
      and $E_2B = A$ where\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 3 & 4 & 1 \\\\ 2 & -7 & -1 \\\
      \\ 8 & 1 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 8 & 1 & 4 \\\\ 2 & -7\
      \ & -1 \\\\ 3 & 4 & 1 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 223
- fields:
    answer: "$$A = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    1/5 & 1/5 & -2/5&   1 & 0 & 0 \\\\\r\n\
      \    1/5 & 1/5 & 1/10&   0 & 1 & 0 \\\\\r\n    1/5 & -4/5 & 1/10&  0 & 0 & 1\r\
      \n    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    1 & 1  & -2&         5 &\
      \ 0 & 0 \\\\\r\n    0 & 0  & 1/2&        -1 & 1 & 0 \\\\\r\n    0 & -1 & 1/2&\
      \       -1 & 0 & 1\r\n    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    1 &\
      \ 1  & -2&         5 & 0 & 0 \\\\\r\n    0 & 1 & -1/2&        1 & 0 & -1 \\\\\
      \r\n    0 & 0 & 1&          -2 & 2 & 0\r\n    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix}\r\
      \n    1 & 1 & 0&         1 & 4 & 0 \\\\\r\n    0 & 1 & 0&         0 & 1 & -1\
      \ \\\\\r\n    0 & 0 & 1&         -2 & 2 & 0\r\n    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$\\\
      begin{pmatrix}\r\n    1 & 0 & 0&         1 & 3 & 1 \\\\\r\n    0 & 1 & 0&  \
      \       0 & 1 & -1 \\\\\r\n    0 & 0 & 1&         -2 & 2 & 0\r\n    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$A^{-1} =\\begin{pmatrix}\r\n1 & 3 & 1 \\\\\r\n0 & 1 & -1 \\\\\r\n-2 & 2\
      \ & 0\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.5.7a
    points: 4
    question: " Use the technique of elementary matrices to find an inverse to\r\n\
      $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1/5 & 1/5 & -2/5 \\\\ 1/5 & 1/5 & 1/10 \\\\ 1/5 & -4/5\
      \ & 1/10\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 224
- fields:
    answer: "The matrix is not invertible.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.5.7d
    points: 2
    question: "Use the technique of elementary matrices to find an inverse to\r\n\
      $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} -8 & 17 & 2 & 1/3 \\\\ 4 & 0 & 2/5 & -9 \\\\ 0&0&0&0\
      \ \\\\ -1 &\r\n13 & 4 & 2\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 225
- fields:
    answer: "$$A(3I - A) = 3A - A^2 = I$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.14
    points: 1
    question: " Show that if a square matrix $A$ satisfies $A^2-3A+I=0$\r\nthen $A^{-1}=3I-A$.\r\
      \n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 226
- fields:
    answer: "Because $A0$ and $0A$ may not have the same size.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.18
    points: 1
    question: "In summarizing properties of matrix arithmetic why is it\r\nnot appropriate\
      \ to write $A0 = 0 = 0A$?\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 227
- fields:
    answer: "If $E$ is an elementary matrix, then $E$ results from performing some\
      \ row\r\noperation on $I$. Let $E_0$ be the matrix that results when the inverse\
      \ of this\r\noperation is performed on $I$. Then $E_0E = I$ and $EE_0 = I$.\r\
      \n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.5.2
    points: 2
    question: "Prove that elementary matrix is invertible and the inverse is also\
      \ an\r\nelementary matrix.\r\n"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 228
- fields:
    answer: "1) => 2)\r\n    Assume $x$ is a solution of $Ax = 0$. Then $x = Ix =\
      \ ^{-1}Ax = 0$\r\n\r\n2) => 3)\r\n    If we solve the related linear system\
      \ of equations for $A$ by Gauss-Jordan\r\n    elminination, then the system\
      \ of equations corresponding to the reduced\r\n    row-echelon form of the augmented\
      \ matrix will be\r\n    $x_i = 0$ since the system has only the trivial solution.\
      \ Thus the reduced\r\n    row-echelon form is $I_n$.\r\n\r\n3) => 4)\r\n   \
      \ There exists $E_i$ such that $E_k \\cdots E_2E_1A = I_n$.\r\n\r\n4) => 1)\r\
      \n    If $A$ is the product of elementary matrices, then since the product of\r\
      \n    invertible matrices is invertible and since elementary matrices are\r\n\
      \    invertible $A$ is invertible.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.5'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 1.5.3
    points: 5
    question: "Prove that TFAE on a $n \\times n$ matrix $A$:\r\n<ol type=\"1\">\r\
      \n<li> $A$ is invertible.\r\n<li> $Ax = 0$ has only the trivial solution.\r\n\
      <li> The reduced row-echelon form of $A$ is $I_n$.\r\n<li> $A$ is expressible\
      \ as a product of elementary matrices.\r\n</ol>"
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 229
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> $Ax = 0$ has only the trivial solution.\r\n<li>\
      \ The reduced row-echelon form of $A$ is $I_n$.\r\n<li> $A$ is expressible as\
      \ a product of elementary matrices.\r\n<li> $Ax = b$ is consistent for every\
      \ $n \\times 1$ matrix $b$.\r\n<li> $Ax = b$ has exactly one solution for every\
      \ $n \\times 1$ matrix $b$\r\n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.6'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.6.4
    points: 2
    question: " State 5 equivalent conditions for a $n \\times n$\r\nmatrix $A$ to\
      \ be invertible."
    section: 6
  model: core.question
  pk: 230
- fields:
    answer: "A diagonal matrix is invertible iff all of its diagonal entries are nonzero,\
      \ in\r\nwhich case its inverse is the diagonal matrix with entries reciprocal\
      \ of the\r\noriginal matrix.\r\n\r\nFurther, power of diagonal matrices are\
      \ easy to compute, as you just raise the\r\ndiagonal entries to the power.\r\
      \n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.7'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: '1.7'
    points: 2
    question: "Explain why diagonal matrices are easy to work with.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 231
- fields:
    answer: "The $n \\times m$ matrix that results from interchanging the rows and\
      \ columns of\r\n$A$.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the transpose of a $m \\times n$ matrix $A$.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 232
- fields:
    answer: "First the matrix *must* be square.\r\n\r\nThen, if it is square, the\
      \ trace is the sum of the elements on the diagonal.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the trace of a matrix.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 233
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\tr(AA^T) = \\sum_{i=1}^m \\mbox{ the entry in rows $i$ and column\
      \ $i$ of\r\n$AA^T$}$$\r\n$$ = \\sum_{i = 1}^m (\\sum_{k = 1}^n (a_{ik})^2)$$\r\
      \n$$ = \\mbox{ the sum of the squares of the entries of $A$ }$$\r\n\r\nThen:\r\
      \n$$AA^T = 0 \\implies tr(AA^T) = 0$$\r\n$$\\implies \\mbox{the sum of squares\
      \ of the entries of $A$ is zero}$$\r\n$$\\implies \\mbox{every entry of $A$\
      \ is zero}$$\r\n$$A = 0$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 1.3.23 & 24
    points: 4
    question: " Prove that if $A$ is an $m \\times n$ matrix, then\r\n$$\\tr(AA^T)\
      \ = s$$\r\nwhere $s$ is the sum of the squares of the entries of $A$. Then use\
      \ this result\r\nto prove that if $A$ is an $m \\times n$ matrix such that $AA^T\
      \ = 0$ or $A^TA = 0\r\n$ then $A = 0$.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 234
- fields:
    answer: "Let $A = (a_{ij})$ and $B = (b_{ij})$. Then\r\n$$((AB)^T)_{ij} = (AB)_{ji}\
      \ = \\sum_{k = 0}^n a_{jk}b_{kj}$$\r\n$$ = \\sum_{k=0}^n (B^T)_{jk}(A^T)_{kj}\
      \ = B^TA^T$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: ''
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Prove that $(AB)^T = B^TA^T$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 235
- fields:
    answer: "From the previous part,\r\n$$A^T(A^{-1})^T = (A^{-1}A)^T = I^T = I$$\r\
      \nand similarly we can show\r\n$$(A^{-1})^TA^T = (AA^{-1})^T = I^T = I$$\r\n\
      \r\nThus $A^T$ has an inverse.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: ''
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Prove that if $A$ is invertible, $(A^T)^{-1} = (A^{-1})^T$.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 236
- fields:
    answer: "$$(A^{-1})^T = (A^T)^{-1} = A^{-1}$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.7'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: Prove that if $A$ is an invertible symmetric matrix then $A^{-1}$ is
      symmetric.
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 237
- fields:
    answer: "1) $(A^T)^T = A$\r\n2) $(A + B)^T = A^T + B^T$\r\n3) $(kA)^T = kA^T$\r\
      \n4) $(AB)^T = B^TA^T$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: State the basic properties of transpose.
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 238
- fields:
    answer: "If $A$ is an invertible matrix, then $A^T$ is also invertible and\r\n\
      $$(A^T)^{-1} = (A^{-1})^T$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.10
    points: 1
    question: ' State the theorem relating transposes and inverses.'
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 239
- fields:
    answer: "1) The transpose of a lower [upper] triangular matrix is upper [lower]\r\
      \ntriangular.\r\n2) The product of lower [upper] triangular matrices is lower\
      \ [upper]\r\ntriangular.\r\n3) A triangular matrix is invertible iff its diagonal\
      \ entries are all nonzero.\r\n4) The inverse of an invertible lower [upper]\
      \ triangular matrix is lower\r\n[upper] triangular matrix.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.7.1
    points: 3
    question: State the basic properties of triangular matrices
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 240
- fields:
    answer: "If $A$ and $B$ are symmetric matrices of the same size:\r\n1) $A^T$ is\
      \ symmetric\r\n2) $A + B$ and $A - B$ is symmetric.\r\n3) $kA$ is symmetric\r\
      \n4) If $A$ is invertible, then $A^{-1}$ is symmetric.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.7.2
    points: 3
    question: " List 4 properties of symmetric matrices.\r\n"
    section: 9
  model: core.question
  pk: 241
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> An inversion is said to occur in a permutation\
      \ $(j_1, j_2, \\ldots, j_n)$ whenever\r\na larger integer precedes a smaller\
      \ one.\r\n<li> A permutation is even or odd as the total number of inversions\
      \ is even or odd.\r\n<li>An elementary product from a square n \\times n matrix\
      \ is any product of $n$\r\nentries no two of which come from the same row or\
      \ same column.A signed elementary product from A is an elementary product\r\n\
      $a_{1j_1}a_{2j_2}\\cdots a_{nj_n}$ multiplied by +1 if the permutation\r\n(j_1j_2\\\
      cdotsj_n) is even and by -1 if it is odd.\r\n<li> The determinant function is\
      \ det(A) = sum of all signed elementary products\r\nof $A$. It is a function\
      \ from the set of all square matrices to the reals.\r\n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Define the following:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> Inversion of a permutation\r\
      \n<li> even [odd] permutation\r\n<li> [signed] Elementary product\r\n<li> Determinant\
      \ function\r\n</ol>"
    section: 10
  model: core.question
  pk: 242
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> inversion number is 8, so even\r\n<li> inversion\
      \ number is 3, so odd.\r\n<li> inversion number is 0, so even.\r\n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: E
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: " Determine the number of inversions in the following\r\npermutations.\
      \ Which are even or odd?\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> (6, 1, 3, 4, 5, 2)\r\n<li>\
      \ (2, 4, 1, 3)\r\n<li> (1, 2, 3, 4)\r\n</ol>\r\n"
    section: 10
  model: core.question
  pk: 243
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $ (-1)^inv(54321) a_15a_24a_33a_42a_51 = (-1)^{10}\
      \ (-3)(-4)(-1)(2)(5) = -120$\r\n<li> $= (-1)^inv(15432) a_11a_25a_34a_43a_52\
      \ = (-1)^{5} (5)(-4)(3)(1)(-2) = -120$\r\n</ol> "
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 2.1.17
    points: 3
    question: " Use the determinant definition to evaluate:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n\
      <li>$\\begin{vmatrix} 0 & 0 & 0 & 0 & -3 \\\\ 0 & 0 & 0 & -4 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 0\
      \ & -1 & 0 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 2 & 0 & 0 & 0 \\\\ 5 & 0 & 0 & 0 & 0\\\\ \\end{vmatrix}$\r\
      \n<li>$\\begin{vmatrix} 5 & 0 & 0 & 0 & 0  \\\\ 0 & 0 & 0 & 0 & -4 \\\\ 0 &\
      \ 0 & 3 & 0 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 0 & 0 & 1 & 0 \\\\ 0 & -2 & 0 & 0 & 0\\\\ \\end{vmatrix}$\r\
      \n</ol>"
    section: 10
  model: core.question
  pk: 244
- fields:
    answer: "If a row of a matrix is zero, then each term will have one element of\
      \ that row\r\nwhich will be zero, thus each signed elementary product has a\
      \ zero.\r\n\r\nThe argument for columns is similar.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 2.1.20
    points: 2
    question: " Prove that if a square matrix $A$ has a row or column of\r\nzeros,\
      \ then det(A) = 0.\r\n"
    section: 10
  model: core.question
  pk: 245
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $\\det(A) = \\det(A^T)$\r\n<li> The determinant\
      \ of an upper triangular, lower triangular or diagonal matrix is the product\
      \ of entries on the main diagonal.\r\n<li> Let $A$ be an $n \\times n$ matrix:\r\
      \n<ol type=\"i\">\r\n<li> If $B$ is the matrix that results when a single row\
      \ or single column of $A$\r\nis multiplied by a scalar $k$, then $\\det(B) =\
      \ k \\det(A)$.\r\n<li> If $B$ is the matrix that results when two rows or columns\
      \ of $A$ are\r\ninterchange, then $\\det(B) = - \\det(A)$.\r\n<li> If $B$ is\
      \ the matrix that results when a multiple of one row of $A$ is added\r\nto another\
      \ row or when a multiple of one column is added to another column then\r\n$\\\
      det(B) = \\det(A)$.\r\n</ol>\r\n<li> If $A$ is a square matrix with two proportional\
      \ rows or two proportional\r\ncolumns, then $\\det(A) = 0$.\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: Thm 2.2.1-5
    points: 6
    question: "State the following properties about determinants:\r\n<ol type=\"a\"\
      >\r\n<li> What is the determinant of a transpose?\r\n<li> What is the determinant\
      \ of a triangular matrix?\r\n<li> What is the effect of elementary row operations\
      \ on the determinant function?\r\n<li> What happens to the determinant function\
      \ if a matrix has proportional rows or columns?\r\n</ol>"
    section: 11
  model: core.question
  pk: 246
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a>\r\n<li> -6\r\n<li> 72\r\n<li> -6\r\n<li> 18\r\n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 2.2.12
    points: 3
    question: "Given that $\\begin{vmatrix} a & b & c \\\\ d & e & f \\\\ g & h &\
      \ i \\\\ \\end{vmatrix} = -6$ find\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $\\begin{vmatrix}\
      \ d & e & f \\\\  g & h & i \\\\ a & b & c \\\\ \\end{vmatrix}$\r\n<li> $\\\
      begin{vmatrix} 3a & 3b & 3c \\\\ -d & -e & -f \\\\ 4g & 4h & 4i \\\\ \\end{vmatrix}$\r\
      \n<li>$\\begin{vmatrix} a+g & b+h & c+i \\\\ d & e & f \\\\ g & h & i \\\\ \\\
      end{vmatrix}$\r\n<li> $\\begin{vmatrix} -3a & -3b & -3c \\\\ d & e & f \\\\\
      \ g -4d & h -4e & i -4f \\\\ \\end{vmatrix}$\r\n</ol>"
    section: 11
  model: core.question
  pk: 248
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> If $A$ is a square matrix then a characteristic\
      \ value $\\lambda$ of $A$ is a\r\none such that $\\lambdaI - A$ has a nontrivial\
      \ solution.\r\n<li> If $A$ is a square matrix then an eigenvector is a nontrivial\
      \ solution of $\\lambdaI - A$.\r\n<li>If $A$ is a square matrix then note that\
      \ the characteristic values are the ones\r\nwhich $\\det(\\lambdaI - A) = 0$.\
      \ This determinant is a polynomial in $\\lambda$,\r\nthe characteristic equation.\r\
      \n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.3'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Define the following terms:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> characteristic\
      \ value of a matrix $A$.\r\n<li> The eigenvector of a matrix $A$.\r\n<li> The\
      \ characteristic equation of a matrix $A$.\r\n</ol>"
    section: 12
  model: core.question
  pk: 249
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li>Let A, B and C be n \\times n matrices that differ\
      \ only in a single row and\r\nassume that C can be obtained by adding the entries\
      \ in this row of A and B.\r\nThen:\r\n    $$\\det(C) = \\det(A) + \\det(B)$.\r\
      \n\r\nThe same result holds for columns.\r\n<li>A square matrix $A$ is invertible\
      \ iff $\\det(A) \\ne 0$.\r\n<li>$$\\det(AB) = \\det(A)\\det(B)$$\r\n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.3'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: Thm 2.3.1-5
    points: 6
    question: "State the following\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li>State the properties\
      \ that characterize the determinant as a function/\r\n<li> Explain the relationship\
      \ between determinants and invertibility.\r\n<li> State the relationship between\
      \ det and matrix multiplication\r\n</ol>"
    section: 12
  model: core.question
  pk: 250
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $A$ is invertible\r\n<li> $Ax = 0$ has only the\
      \ trivial solution\r\n<li> The reduced row-echelon form of $A$ is $I_n$.\r\n\
      <li> $A$ is expressible as a product of elementary matrices.\r\n<li> $Ax =b$\
      \ is consistent for every $n \\times 1$ matrix $b$.\r\n<li> $Ax =b$ has exactly\
      \ one solution for every $n \\times 1$ matrix $b$.\r\n<li> $\\det(A) \\ne 0$\r\
      \n</ol>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.3'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: Thm 2.3.6
    points: 3
    question: State 6 equivalent conditions to a square matrix being invertible using  only
      linear systems, matrix arithmetic and determinants.
    section: 12
  model: core.question
  pk: 251
- fields:
    answer: "Do thi